Chapter 38: Walpurgisnacht

JUPITER: Je dirais donc: "Jeune homme, allez-vous-en! Que cherchez-vous ici? Vous voulez faire valoir vos droits? Eh! vous êtes ardent et fort, vous feriez un brave capitaine dans une armée bien batailleuse, vous avez mieux à faire qu'à régner sur une ville à demi morte, une charogne de ville tourmentée par les mouches. Les gens d'ici sont de grands pécheurs, mais voici qu'ils se sont engagés dans la voie du rachat. Laissez-les, jeune homme, laissez-les, respectez leur douloureuse enterprise, éloignez-vous sur la pointe des pieds. … Et que leur donnerez-vous en échange? Des digestions tranquilles, la paix morose des provinces et l'ennui, ah! l'ennui si quotidien du bonheur. Bon voyage, jeune homme, bon voyage; l'ordre d'une cité et l'ordre des âmes sont instables: si vous y touchez, vous provoquerez une catastrophe. (Le regardent dans les yeux.) Une terrible catastrophe qui retombera sur vous.

ZEUS: Well, I'd say something like this. "My lad, get you gone! What business have

you here? Do you wish to enforce your rights? Yes, you're brave and strong and spirited. I can

see you as a captain in an army of good fighters. You have better things to do than reigning over a dead-and-alive city, a carrion city plagued by flies. These people are great sinners but, as you see, they're working out their atonement. Let them be, young fellow, let them be; respect their sorrowful endeavor, and begone on tiptoe. ... What, moreover, could you give

them in exchange? Good digestions, the gray monotony of provincial life, and the boredom —

ah, the soul-destroying boredom — of long days of mild content. Go your way, my lad, go your

way. The repose of cities and men's souls hangs on a thread; tamper with it and you bring

disaster. (Looking him in the eyes.) A disaster which will recoil on you.

-Les Mouches, Jean-Paul Sartre

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

April 30th, 1999

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

Now

Harry snapped his fingers.

To his left, through the open door back into the Establishment, he could hear several people gasp at the gesture - those who knew the legend. But in front of him, the two iterations of Bellatrix Black only stared at him.

"What was that, little man? Another ultimate weapon?" asked the one on the left, her voice mocking. Her right eye was only a torn nugget of ruined red flesh, bloody on her cheek, but it didn't seem to bother her.

In spite of himself and in spite of everything, Harry felt a mad giggle rising. He fought it back.

"Yes," he said. "Yes, you could say that."

"The Empty Fort," the two witches said, almost in unison. An identical expression of contemptuous glee was spreading on each of their faces.

"Where is the Dark Lord?" asked the one on the right. They raised their wands again, pointing them at Harry.

"Muffliato," said Harry, for some semblance of privacy, "I cut off his hands and wiped his memory and turned him into a rock. But I was worried that wasn't enough after it almost went wrong, and so I ripped his mind out of his body and imprisoned it in a fungus that I keep inside of a fancy box." He paused. "Did you want the box? I can have it gift-wrapped, I suppose."

"Stalling billy dolly," said the one on the right, sneering. She cocked her head to the side.

"Twist a while and you'll tell a truer tale," said the other. Her tongue poked out of her mouth, pinkish and crude, and licked blood from her upper lip.

From the corner of his eye, Harry could see movement. He raised his left hand sharply, to signal whoever it was to stop.

"No, that's the truth, actually," he said, calmly. "But I will trade you an even better one, if you answer a question of mine." He had many, actually. What is that duplication spell? Did Voldemort know it? It duplicated your arm - could it duplicate any artifact? Is the ritual sacrifice permanent, or can you heal that eye later?

The Bellatrix on the right giggled. "No time, billy. Bumbling bungling billy. I'm heavy with the milk of your death." Then the levity vanished from her face, suddenly and completely, and her lips tightened. "Twist."

"Crucio," cast the other.

And there was pain.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

ORESTE: Il y a des hommes qui naissent engagés: ils n'ont pas le choix, on les a jetés sur un chemin, au bout du chemin il y a un acte qui les attend, leur acte; ils vont, et leurs pieds nus pressent fortement la terre et s'écorchent aux cailloux. Ça te paraît vulgaire, à toi, la joie d'aller quelque part? Et il y en a d'autres, des silencieux, qui sentant au fond de leur cœur le poids d'images troubles et terrestres; leur vie a été changée parce que, un jour de leur enfance, à cinq ans, à sept ans… C'est bon: ce ne sont pas des hommes supérieurs. Je savais déjà, moi, à sept ans, que j'étais exilé; les odeurs et les sons, le bruit de la pluie sur les toits, les tremblements de la lumière, je les laissais glisser le long de mon corps et tomber autour de moi; je savais ui'ils appartenaient aux autres, et que je ne pourrais jamais en faire mes souvenirs. Car les souvenirs sont de grasses nourritures pour ceux qui possèdent les maisons, les bêtes, les domestiques et les champs.

ORESTES: Some men are born bespoken; a certain path has been assigned them, and at its end there is something they must do, a deed allotted. So on and on they trudge, wounding their bare feet on the flints. I suppose that strikes you as vulgar—the joy of going somewhere definite. And there are others, men of few words, who bear deep down in their hearts a load of dark imaginings; men whose whole life was changed because one day in childhood, at the age of five or seven— Right; I grant you these are no great men. When I was seven, I know I had no home, no roots. I let sounds and scents, the patter of rain on housetops, the golden play of sunbeams, slip past my body and fall round me—and I knew these were for others, I could never make them my memories. For memories are luxuries reserved for people who own houses, cattle, fields, and servants.

-Les Mouches, Jean-Paul Sartre

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

April 30th, 1993

Office of Harry Potter-Evans-Verres, Hogwarts, Scotland

Six years ago

It had been difficult to visit his parents, as always. It wasn't that it made him unhappy, exactly, or even that it was uncomfortable. It was the sense of loss that bothered him, waiting in the wings.

There was always a huge amount of things to talk about. Mum would always ask after Hermione and Draco and Minerva, although she didn't want to hear about the "politics" or the "magical things," but about how Minerva and Draco were coping with their losses, or about how Hermione was doing so much better these days. She'd met Granville, Hermione's phoenix, at Christmastime, and had been so charmed that she'd been rendered speechless. Granville had given her a feather, and Mum kept it on her vanity mirror.

Dad had his own interests and endless suggestions. He made spirited attempts to talk about magic, but really the possibility of reforming a society was what he always wanted to talk about, sitting down with Harry at the kitchen table for long chats. They'd both read their Heinlein, Asimov, Gibson, Stephenson… they would sit down after dinner and debate possible routes for a future society for hours, talking until their tea was cold and the rest of the world was asleep. How could you intelligently plan for a world of eternal youth, with no disease or poverty? What steps did you need to take now, and in what order? Harry had the sense that his father thought the entire thing was still a bit unreal, and that Harry might be exaggerating his own role in the world these days… but what Oxford liberal sci-fi fan could resist the opportunity to talk about the way a society should be run - a potential Church of All Worlds, or Foundation, or Freeside, or Neo-Victorian England, depending on the choices they made?

His father had paused at one point, last night, to marvel at that. "Do you really think you're capable of making these decisions, son? Do you think anyone could make them in your place? Account for every possibility and plan out an entire civilization?" A pause. "Does anyone even have the right to try?"

"If I could leave it up to the wisdom of crowds and market forces, I would," Harry had replied, staring at the kitchen table. "I can't, and there's no one else to take my place. I have my Fellowship, and I'm not going to refuse the Ring just because it seems impossible or arrogant. I have to try."

His father was thoughtful for a quiet moment, and then smiled. "Does that make me Elrond?"

Harry had rolled his eyes, even as his heart answered, Yes.

But through all of his visits, Harry knew - even if they didn't - that he was going to have to stop coming to visit. Not forever - not on the scale at which mankind would be operating soon, an unlimited life of unlimited possibility - but for a long time. Already, he'd been coming to visit less often. Soon, he was going to have to ask them to come visit him, instead. And eventually, he'd need to resign himself to letters. He probably should already have done that for their own safety, if for no other reason. They were risking an eternity of life and he was risking the fate of the world every time he had contact. Harry had needed to think about the possibilities (never refuse to think about something, not even once), but he didn't like to dwell on them. Kidnapping, blackmail, torture… it was the fate of the world and the species in the balance.

So ever since Harry had returned to Hogwarts, massive defense force and five decoys going along for the ride, he'd been quiet. He'd spoken to Minerva and given her word from his parents, and then gone straight up to his office through the twisting corridors and up the moving stairs, and when he got there he'd exchanged only the barest of pleasantries with Hermione while getting the Stone back from her and destroying his facsimile. Harry hadn't been unfriendly, but he didn't feel like he had the emotional energy to discuss his feelings, so he'd kept some distance. He got to work on that day's patients as they were cleared and escorted by the aurors, and stayed quiet and polite and distant.

When Draco had gotten there, he'd taken in the look on Harry's face at a glance, and hadn't said much more than good morning.

The first two patients of the day had been easy enough. The first, an older man, had needed his right arm healed from the long and painful twisting that had come from a curse in his younger days. Certain curses were beyond the power of healing spells - indeed, sometimes that was their whole point - and it had been a wonderful thing to see the look on the man's face as his pain faded away for the first time in thirty years. The man had moved and flexed the hand that had been frozen into a claw for decades, and eventually had begun to weep. Harry had accepted his thanks, refused his money, and sent him on his way.

The second patient was even easier: a child born with a chronic seizure disorder. Potions could keep it in check, such as the Caesarian Draught (a potion which had nothing to do with obstetrics, Harry had discovered after one amusing misunderstanding), but that was ruinously expensive. Even taking extraordinary care, it had been easy for Harry to repair the lesions on the child's brain. Unfortunately, he hadn't been able to figure out the cause; the shapes of the lesions, as best he could tell, didn't really point to any specific pathology. Harry had made notes and consulted a manual on differential diagnosis of atypical neural lesions, but had needed to chalk it up to hydrocephaly at the moment and put off further research until later.

He thought he'd have time to dig into it that afternoon. The aurors were slow to vet potential patients, much to Harry's frustration, and despite his wish to scale things up, he probably wouldn't get to see many more than twelve patients that day. He needed to bring on more healers and more aurors, or work out a different system.

Harry was ready when the two aurors escorted in a third patient. It was another older man, and it looked like another easy case. The man had terrible burn scars on the lower part of his face, covering his chin and one of his cheeks with pale, knotted tissue. The man's eyes were wide, staring around with obvious alarm. It wasn't uncommon. Across the room, for example, Hermione was healing someone who'd come in so terrified they were outright sobbing. It soon passed.

Well, usually it soon passed. Harry glanced at the corner, where a short brunette woman was sitting quietly, her hands folded in her lap, her eyes vacant. One of the rescues from Azkaban - a French woman named Charlevoix. She, too, had been rescued from pain, only to remain in a state of near-catatonia. She broke out into screams if she was separated from Hermione. They let her stay.

"Hello, sir," Harry said. He tried to make his voice warm, and mustered up a smile. "Just lie down on the bed, there, if you don't mind. There's nothing to worry about… you're going to feel a lot better, very soon."

The old man lay down without protest, gingerly reclining on the bed. Harry sat in a chair next to it. He lay his wand on his lap. The man was frightened. "Are you all right, sir? Nervous?"

Harry glanced at the aurors who escorted the man. One of them shrugged - nothing to contribute. They stood silently at the foot of the bed: an obvious presence of force. It was just a precaution, as were the twelve other aurors in the room. Everyone was carefully screened and had to submit to Veritaserum before they were permitted to receive healing, and before entering they were disenchanted and dispelled and everything else an auror could do. Precaution was taken against Imperius and Confundus… even against false or locked memories. There were traps and wards and yet more traps, and outside assault was as impossible as they could make it.

"I… I don't… I'm sorry," murmured the patient with a quavering voice.

"For what?" Harry asked, smiling.

"I came for… for my face and chest. All burnt, long ago. I'd forgotten…"

Harry made the connection. "You'd locked away the memory of how it happened?"

"Not me. St. Mungo's. They'd had to… I couldn't... I…" The man's face twisted, stiff flesh on his chin rippling, and he clenched his eyes shut. Tears began to roll down his cheeks.

"I'm sorry you lost that protection," Harry said, gently. "We can help you with that again, if you want. Or we can put you in touch with someone we work with… a type of special healer who helps people with problems that they can't face and don't want to forget."

"The boy… my boy," gasped the man. Harry just sat quietly. There was nothing he could say - he needed to just let the man take a moment to work through whatever had happened.

"Th- There was a fire…" said the man, haltingly. "My fault. I wanted… I'm Salvation Starr, maybe you've… I am a pyromancer. There is none greater in Britain." Harry hadn't heard of the man, but that wasn't that surprising. Despite everything that had happened, he'd only learned about magic itself two years ago. There was still a lot of common knowledge that had escaped him, and there were famous magical researchers that he'd never heard of, Chocolate Frog card or no. Harry glanced at one of the aurors again, and the auror nodded in confirmation.

The patient raised his arms up, and hugged himself. He turned onto his side, away from Harry. "So many have been hurt. I myself… There was a fire. There was a terrible fire. I wanted to find a barrier against all flame. Ever since the fall of Sontag… I wanted to find a way to stop it… stop such a fire-" The man stopped speaking, his voice strangled away into a pained squeak by his grief.

"An accident? With your research?" Harry said, gently. The wizarding settlement of Sontag had been burned in the second goblin rebellion of 1612. It had been long-abandoned by that time - making its destruction more of a threat than a real attack - but it had still been considered a tragedy. None of the wizards present then had been able to extinguish the magical flames the goblins had wielded against Sontag, and the incident was always described in history books with an ominous tone.

"My boy… he…" Salvation's shoulders shook, and he lapsed back into silence.

"Sir…you had a son, sir?" said the other auror. He sounded surprised - that must not have turned up in their investigation. Usually they were so careful… so slow that I have been complaining about it.

The first auror asked, "Are you quite sure that-"

"Not my child," said the man, his voice thick. "My nephew. A Muggle. But he was like my child. I loved him like my child. My boy. My boy..."

The auror nodded slowly. "Yes, sir."

"I'm so sorry, sir," said Harry. He stood up, as quietly as he could. "We're going to have you back another day, I think, sir."

Salvation rolled back over, suddenly, and snatched at the hem of Harry's sleeve with a desperate hand. The aurors drew their wands so quickly that Harry barely even saw them move, but didn't intervene.

"Wait!" said Salvation, his voice harsh. He slid his legs to the side and sat up on the bed, not letting go of Harry. "You're the Boy-Who-Lived. You can… I know you can…"

"I can't bring back the dead, sir. I'm so sorry, but I can't…" Not yet, thought Harry, looking over at Draco, who was sitting with Hermione at the other end of the room, helping her with her patient. But I will. I have promises to keep. I will.

He looked back down at the patient. "I'm so sorry, but I can't bring him back. I wish I could, believe me I do, but I can't."

"He would stay with me, sometimes. I had a room for him. He loved dragons. Always loved dragons. I used Welsh Greens, sometimes, and he would sit behind the wards and stare for hours at them. Big posters of dragons all over the walls. Wanted to see a Chinese Fireball, one day," husked Salvation.

"I didn't know he was in the house... I didn't know he was in the house… I would never have been experimenting if I'd known they were going to come early. My sister and my boy… The cursed fire, I thought I could stop it with my new ward. I thought I had it. I never would have… I didn't know..." The man's voice broke into a sob. Then it cut off, and his eyes fixed themselves on Harry again, coming back from some far-off place of grief and regret. "Bring back my boy. I know things… I went far abroad when I was young. I know how to do things. I have many things. You can have all my knowledge, everything I have. Bring back my boy. Bring back Davey."

Harry shook his head again. This had gone on long enough, and even though it seemed cruel, he needed to defuse the situation before it got out of hand. "I'm sorry, sir."

He raised one hand to give a signal to the aurors, but paused, staring past them at the entrance to his office, where a piece of parchment folded into an airplane had just glided into the room. It was one of the memos they used at the Ministry of Magic, lazily propelling itself with slow flaps of papery wings.

"Bring back my boy," said Salvatore again, more quietly. "Please… I'm begging you. I know you have the power. I have much to offer. Old rituals and ancient spells, long forgotten by all others. I have sacrificed much to gain them - done grim things for grim people - but I will give them over to you. I have been to the nave of Beatus Payens and I have been to the land of the Tuatha… I have traded power for power, to learn all I could of flame and fire. You can have all that I know. Every rune in my books. Every bit of flame. Please… you must. I didn't… oh Merlin… I didn't know he was there, he was an innocent, don't you see, I didn't know he was there. Bring him back." He steadied himself. "You must, Harry Potter."

The aurors were moving on their own account, and one of them came to Salvatore's elbow. "Master Starr," he said, gently. Harry pulled away from the patient. Salvatore didn't resist, but didn't let go; his hand remained suspended in the air, clutching at nothing as Harry's sleeve left his grip.

"Please, sir," said Salvatore, but the emotion had left his voice. It sounded flat and full of sadness.

Harry stepped towards the memo, which was sailing along sedately, and held out his hand. The parchment plane landed on his palm. Behind him, the auror helped Salvatore to his feet.

When Harry opened the parchment, he found that it really was a standard Ministry memo, sealed and embossed in the normal way. But it was a very long way from home. The seal was cracked in the middle, and the rest of the memo was creased into squares and crinkled with two parallel lines: the thing had been folded up and sent here by owl. Harry opened it, frowning.

The top few inches of a newspaper had been pasted to the parchment: that evening's edition of The Daily Prophet. There was no time marking, but it was only the early afternoon - this was a message from the future. At least four hours, but perhaps as far as six.

TRAGEDY: POTTER ATTACKED, CLINIC RAZED

Nothing more.

Why send only this? Harry thought. But there was no time to think it through. When given an anonymous warning, the course was clear (or at least, seemed obvious enough to Harry): react quickly, but in an unorthodox way. He couldn't ignore the message, especially since it might have come from the future, but if you reacted predictably to an anonymous warning, then you were only granting your enemy the power to control you.

Harry's thoughts moved in a flash. First-level response, standard lockdown. Vulnerable to specific kinds of attacks. Obvious alternative - evacuation - has the same problem. Brief message and unorthodox delivery style that bypassed other viewers… points to some betrayal or widespread attack… an owl takes twelve minutes to get here from the Ministry… an ally there, betraying a conspiracy? Why anonymous? Warning was sent from as far as six hours in the future… a message there, clearly. The attack will happen within the next six hours… it will do serious damage, but since this message was sent, we have the power to mitigate or change that. Still, though, the first question was dragging on his thoughts, demanding attention: If you're going to help, why send only this? Is the future outcome - the alternative that prompted the message - so terrible that you don't want it known?

"You must," said Salvatore from behind him, raising his voice again. Hermione and Draco were looking over in alarm, now, and the pair of aurors with their patient and the ones at the door had drawn their wands.

"Harry Potter, I demand it. He cannot remain gone - remain burned." Salvatore's voice cracked at the last word. "You will."

And with a sinking feeling in his stomach, Harry realized another possible reason for the message.

Sabotage from the future. Information cannot go any further than six hours back in time. So right now, at this moment, we can't go back and prevent-

"You will!" said Salvatore again, and Harry hadn't even turned around before he felt the bloom of heat on his back.

"This is an insane thing you're trying, boy," Moody had said to them, last year. "There's too much evil and too much madness in the world. Too much damn randomness. You can't account for everything. We can test the people who visit, but any security system in any fortress is based on keeping people out. It's not like in the Muggle world. A Muggle without a weapon is about as dangerous as a dog. A powerful wizard without a wand, on the other hand, could be tasting your blood within minutes. You can't secure your most important assets - you, the Stone, Voldie - if you also need to allow open access to them. It's an impossible problem."

"That just means that no one has ever been prepared or paranoid or clever enough," Harry had replied, with far too much self-assurance. "No problem is impossible."

"Immobinnghhh," Harry heard one auror say, the spell cut off in a grunt of pain, an instant before he felt an sweeping force pluck his legs out from underneath him and lift him into the air, like the scooping palm of a gentle giant. He was hurled across the room in a tumble, the world spinning around him in a confusion of red and grey, before hitting the opposite wall hard enough to drive the air out of his lungs. He found himself looking up at Hermione, Draco, and the pair of aurors that had been escorting her patient. The aurors had jumped in front of the other two and the patient, and were already acting - indeed, they had reacted so quickly that one of them had already raised a shield of brightly-glowing silver spheres the size of golf balls.

Salvatore barely even used incantations, and had no wand, but he had filled the air with flame, nonetheless. In moments, it had blocked out everything from Harry's sight but its own bright light, tumbling and toiling in the air like a living thing. He could smell hair burning and knew that he was on fire, and he beat at his head and face, flapping at himself and trying to smother the flames, screaming. He had a moment's glimpse of the aurors - they were burnt and burning, too, one of them also screaming, his face a blackened thing. Draco tackled that one, putting his wand to her chest and trying to do something. Hermione was already standing, her own wand raised, casting curses. Charlevoix was cowering behind her, her arms wrapped in front of her head in an attempt to protect herself. Hermione's pale face was lit a hellish orange by the fire-glow.

Harry couldn't follow the combat, couldn't find his wand, could barely hold on to his sanity as he yanked his robes up and tried to smother the flames on his body with them, ripping them with desperate yanks until they moved freely and slamming them down again and again to try to beat out the fire.

By the time he had put out the flames, the room was already so full of smoke that he was coughing and choking. He couldn't find his wand, oh god where was his wand… what did he have… He jammed his hand into his pouch and tried to choke out some words, but he could only cough and hack, doubling up, and god he could barely even see, everything was just a reddish-orange haze. What was the sign language - he couldn't remember, it was gone from his head - couldn't breathe couldn't see… Just thick smoke everywhere.

Harry could hear someone chanting, and if he hadn't already been panicking, he probably would have dissolved in terror when he recognized the words. "Az-reth. Az-reth. Az-reth." He remembered Voldemort saying that, and he remembered the thing that had come at that call.

The red-lit smoke turned scarlet.

Someone grabbed his legs, and Harry kicked at the hands, wildly. They snatched him with incredible strength - inhuman strength- and he felt himself lifted bodily as he was hauled into the air. He would have screamed again, but when he tried to draw a breathe it came with the burning harshness of smoke, and he spasmed with coughing again, sucking poisonous air and choking on it.

The hands threw him, and he was flying.

He landed hard, smashing into a corner of stone, and felt a riot of pain in his ribs, made worse by his hacking and coughing. But the air was fresher where he'd landed. His thoughts were a confused stream - where was he, why was he in the hall, what was happening - but he could breathe. He sucked in the air and the dimming world grew sharper.

Harry rolled onto his side, still gasping, and looked back at his office. Thick black smoke was roiling inside, pouring out in a dense cloud.

As he watched, it began to thin, and he could make out shapes within it. Figures shouting words and casting spells, colored light tinging the smoke. One figure stood at the center, surrounding by a bright glow of scarlet that highlighted it like a silhouette against the sun. That broken man. Salvatore. His Fiendfyre was some monstrous snake, and it was burning away all the smoke in the room as it lashed out again and again. There were five aurors still standing, protecting each other and the patient and Draco and Charlevoix. Harry knew that more would be on the way, here within the minute.

And there was Hermione.

It was impossible to fight Fiendfyre, of course. Nothing could beat that, not that they could imagine. All you could do was hope to avoid it, and even that seemed impossible. But somehow, she was doing it. Every time it lashed out, she would leap or dodge or duck, sending another curse Salvatore's way, forcing the creature of hellish fire to return to him. The aurors poured on their own attacks, a blur of aggressive spellcasting that Harry could barely follow. The very nature of the Fiendfyre consumed most curses, but even that extravagance was beginning to prove insufficient. Salvatore was badly wounded. Blood was pouring out of a ragged hole in his stomach, and he was missing some fingers on one hand.

Harry could hear the man screaming, over and over. "NO! NO! NO!" He screamed and threw waves of flame, beat back attacks with living fire, and flooded the room with heat and smoke. "You can't!" he screamed.

An instant later, a curse hit him in the chest, and he collapsed, his face lifeless.

The Fiendfyre flared up and roared with leprous flame, surging larger and larger as the control left it, and it ran free. It grew brighter and brighter, its wide coils and thrashing,

An auror fell, obliterated to the waist by flame. Another had already lost an arm. Draco was screaming. Harry could see Hermione fall, withering like a leaf in the summer heat.

Granville called. The phoenix's cry was piercing and pure, like the voice of a god.

Harry saw the creature for only a moment as it flashed past him, soaring with the speed and determination of an arrow. It swept overhead with a streak of golden flame.

It never hesitated. It flew at the Fiendfyre with a courage and joy so pure that Harry's heart broke to see it.

Gold met scarlet. With a sound like thunder, both vanished. Nothing was left in their wake but stinking smoke and the echoes of a phoenix's last call.

He felt hands on him again - an auror, roughly pulling at his wounds and laying a wand on him.. More were racing in past her, charging towards his office. Spells cleared the air, cleared his view.

He saw burned and dying aurors, thrashing. Several of them still standing, staggering and injured but with wands raised high. Draco, weeping.

He saw Charlevoix, her hands a tangle of charred flesh. Cradling something.

Cradling Hermione.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

ÉLECTRE: Il fait beau. Partout, dans la plaine, des hommes lèvant la tête et disent: "Il fait beau", et ils sont contents. O bourreaux de vous-mêmes, avez-vous oublié cet humble contentement du paysan qui marche sur sa terre et qui dit: "Il fait beau"? Vous voilà les bras ballants, la tête basse, respirant à peine. Vos morts se collent contre vous, et vous demeurez immobiles dans la crainte de les bousculer au moindre geste. Ce serait affreux, n'est ce-pas? si vos mains traversaient soudain une petite vapeur moite, l'âme de votre père ou de votre aïeul? Mais regardez-moi: j'étends les bras, je m'élargis, et je m'étire comme un homme qui s'éveille, j'occupe ma place au soleil, toute ma place. Est-ce que le ciel me tombe sur la tête? Je danse, voyez, je danse, et je ne sense rien que le souffle du vent dans mes cheveux. Où sont les morts? Croyez-vous qu'ils dansent avec moi, en mesure?

ELECTRA: The sun is shining. Everywhere down in the plains men are looking up and saying:

"It's a fine day," and they're happy. Are you so set on making yourselves wretched that you've

forgotten the simple joy of the peasant who says as he walks across his fields: "It's a fine day"?

No, there you stand hanging your heads, moping and mumbling, more dead than alive. You're

too terrified to lift a finger, afraid of jolting your precious ghosts if you make any movement.

That would be dreadful, wouldn't it, if your hand suddenly went through a patch of clammy mist,

and it was your grandmother's ghost! Now look at me. I'm spreading out my arms freely, and I'm

stretching like someone just roused from sleep. I have my place in the sunlight, my full place and to spare. And does the sky fall on my head? Now I'm dancing, see, I'm dancing, and all I feel is the wind's breath fanning my cheeks. Where are the dead? Do you think they're dancing with me, in step?

-Les Mouches, Jean-Paul Sartre

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Wearily, Harry mounted the stairs to the workroom of the Headmistress. In his pocket were four phials of blood from Vincent Crabbe, obtained after two hours of intimidation and veiled threats. Moody had helped, along with two aurors Moody had trained himself - an older one named Hedley Kwannon, and one barely out of training named Nymphadora Tonks. The glass phials, filled with the blood of Hermione's enemy, clicked against each other as Harry climbed the stairs.

He pushed open the door. It was silent inside. Reddish light from the dawn illuminated the alchemical diagram on the floor: nested and interlaced circles and pentagons surrounding a central pentacle. He'd been here once before, when he first demonstrated partial Transfiguration - so long ago! - and the room didn't look to have been used since that visit.

"Mad-Eye's not here yet. We have to wait," said Draco's voice from his left. Harry started, and stepped forward to see that the boy was sitting at the base of the circular wall, head slumped forward.

"How are you, Draco?" asked Harry, quietly.

"This was your fault," Draco replied.

"I know."

"No, you don't, you stupid piece of arrogant filth," said the Slytherin boy, but there was no anger in his voice. It was disconcertingly flat, with nothing but weariness and sorrow - the sorrow of someone who had been required to endure too much, too soon. "You think that you just made a mistake. You'd do the same thing all over again, but you'd just be sure to include one more trap. One more level of manipulation or cleverness. You don't see that the entire thing is… impossible. It's just impossible, and you won't see that, and Hermione just keeps listening to you, and now she's paid for your stupidity."

"I know."

"And even worse, this is just another reminder of why I was stupid to ever trust you - to ever get involved in this asinine little play. Your goals are… mad. Insane. But you don't recognize that, since you don't recognize any limits to… to… to anything."

It was more than that, of course. It was even more than the terrible suffering and temporary absence of Hermione, as badly as that, too, had hurt the other boy. There was something more.

You're worried that I can't deliver on my promises… that you've placed hope in false prophecies and a false prophet. You're wondering if I am just a freak prodigy of Muggle science who looked really impressive in schoolyard antics, since he had a whole other world of tricks to steal, and who got lucky once… but who might just not be able to cut it in the real world.

Draco looked up at him, and the boy looked unspeakably sad - like he'd lost something precious.

You're worried I'll never be able to bring your father back, after all.

"Draco, there is-"

"Shut up," interrupted Draco, his voice hardening. "Shut up and let's just wait without talking. You're always talking, but it didn't help her, did it? Her phoenix burned and she burned. And now she's dead, again, just like she was afraid would happen." Draco's eyes were red, but dry. "She told me that… those months when she was trying to get her Patronus. To meet your expectations. She told me that she was terrified of dying again and that she thought that was probably the reason she couldn't do it. 'I wake up screaming sometimes, Draco,' she said."

"Stop," said Harry, squeezing his eyes shut.

Draco sounded more like he was scolding himself than Harry. His words were black and bitter. "And now she's all burned up and dead again, and it's your fault again. Because you don't understand what is possible, and you talk and you push - oh, Merlin, it always sounds so insane when you first start talking, but by the end of the conversation it's the rest of the world that seems insane, and how could I ever think that made sense? How could anyone be that damned arrogant?"

Harry turned away, blindly. His eyes burned with hot tears. For a moment, despite all of his resolutions, he almost called on his dark side: to cool him and calm him and solve this problem. The cold emptiness of Voldemort's thought patterns would have been preferable to this. Null was better than negative.

But he didn't, because one did not abandon carefully-considered decisions during the exact sort of situation for which you had prepared them. All he could do, instead, was sink to the stone, slick with dust under his fingers, and cry.

After a time, his shoulders stopped heaving, and his breathing slowed from great shuddering gasps into quiet evenness. Draco had said nothing, and hadn't moved. When Harry pushed himself up into a sitting position, he saw through a smear of tears that the other boy was just staring at him, dully, with red-rimmed eyes.

"I…" began Harry, but he found that he didn't have any words. He fell silent again.

Eventually, he stood up and drew his wand. "Scourgify," he cast, his voice heavy. The spell cleared away the dust. Putting away his wand, Harry opened his pouch and reached in. "Cauldron," he said to it, and felt the metal lip of a small cauldron leap into his hand. He pulled it free of the pouch, which distended to permit its passage, and set it in the center of the diagram.

Harry sat down next to it, and took the phials of blood out of his pocket. He set them down next to the cauldron.

Draco pushed himself to his feet, and walked over. Digging into the pocket of his robes - still the same burned ones, had he not had a chance to change? no, of course... he left them on for effect - he pulled out a small bag of soft bicorn skin and dropped it down next to the other objects. The flesh of a servant, willingly given by Odette Charlevoix.

Moody would be here soon, with a piece of bone from Hermione's father. He had insisted on doing this part himself, saying that he didn't trust anyone else to invisibly infiltrate Happy Smiles Family Dentistry, stun one of the owners, extract a chip of bone while the man was unconscious, and fix any memories afterwards. It was a thankless task, and Harry thought that some part of Moody's insistence was probably repentance. Moody blamed himself for the attack, almost as much as he blamed Harry. "We weren't paranoid enough," he had said, bitterly. It was as heavy an indictment as he could deliver.

They waited in silence.

Finally, Harry spoke again. "I tried. I tried as hard as I could. I thought through everything and planned it out and assembled every bit of information… I counted forty-three known threats and planned for eight kinds of unknowns. We had just… layers of security and plans." Draco knew most of them, of course. He'd helped, along with Moody and Hermione and Bones.

There were fat folders, stuffed with parchments - or had been, anyway, before the fire ate the hidden boltholes that had been serving as safes. Dossiers on people and information on countries: CHINA. Overview: Continued worries about European and British dominance in magic, may seek to strike before new regime rises. Often isolates self and seeks to extend power over Ten Thousand, but pragmatic leadership points to a willingness to shift tactics, if seems advantageous. Traditional value for immortality, connected to long specialization in potioneering. Informal and formal power structures largely mirror each other; little vulnerability to factionalization but suggests opportunity to shift key functionaries and alter trajectory of entire country. And so on.

Plans within plans, contingency upon contingency: living and adaptable Matryoshka dolls whirling in a furious dance. A location that couldn't be stormed by force, allies watching other allies, security measures and magical wards that could cut off the life of an attacker in moments. And none of it had done any good when the mind of a powerful wizard had broken. He had died, but so had others. So had Hermione.

"It's not your fault that you can't do the impossible. It's only your fault that you try the impossible, and other people pay for it," replied Draco. He stared down at Harry. "You can't plan for everything. The world is dark and people are vicious. Even the good ones are vicious, and the bad ones are worse, and the crazy ones do things you couldn't possibly predict. You can't control the universe, Harry Potter-Evans-Verres, you miserable, arrogant little scrub."

Harry was silent once more, and looked away, unable to meet Draco's gaze. He hugged his knees. Draco turned away, walking heavily towards the door.

There's too much evil and too much madness in the world, Moody had said. Too much damn randomness.

You can't control the universe.

"I don't accept that," he whispered, as much for himself as for Draco.

"What?" demanded Draco, turning back around, his voice incredulous - angry now, where he hadn't been before.

"I don't accept that," Harry repeated, more loudly. He looked up. "I do not accept that."

"You can't-"

Harry lurched to his feet, swaying slightly, his kneecaps popping from the sudden shift. There was iron in his voice, now. It wasn't cold iron; it wasn't the chill metal of his dark side, icy with hateful clarity. It was iron at a white heat. He glowed with it.

"No," Harry said, his voice as certain as a hammerblow.

"No," he repeated.

"No," he said again.

"I do not accept that. I do not accept death. I do not accept decline. I do not accept madness. I do not accept randomness. They are all part of the universe, and they are all important… but I do not - mankind does not - have to accept them," said Harry. "If you want out of this, then say so. If you want to lead a different life, then you know I won't begrudge you that. I will make that happen, and that choice I once gave you will always be yours: you may choose another path and you will not hear a word of regret from me. Your preferences are sacred. So if you think this can't be done… go." Harry's face was grim. "But I'm not going."

Harry walked towards Draco until he was inches away from the other boy. Iron was bright in his words.

"Right now, there is a little girl somewhere in the world. She's a small thing for her age, with big eyes. She loves her big brother. She wants to be just like her mother when she grows up. But tonight, there will be an accident. A rotten tree will collapse as the little girl climbs it, and she'll tumble to the ground, and she'll land badly. And she'll die. And then her big eyes will be gone, and her brother will never see her again, and she'll never grow up to be like her mother. Everything she ever was or will be: gone and dead and buried.

"Her brother will deal with his grief, in time, and may even find solace and strength in stories about how death is necessary. Her mother will cry and hurt, but in time it will hurt less, and she'll focus more on her son, and eventually the loss will fade until it's just a nagging ache in her heart - that never quite leaves. And the world will go on, because it's happened every day in every way, and we have learned how to manage the loss.

"But it doesn't have to be that way. And I don't just mean saving that little girl, or Hermione, or even your father, Draco, but every little girl and friend and father. People die every day and they always have but I do not accept it."

But something of Harry's heat had communicated itself with his words, and Draco's eyes were lit as bright as the red glow of Fiendfyre. He seized the front of Harry's robes, twisting his fists in them, and shoved as hard as he could. Harry stumbled backwards, foot skidding, and only barely kept his balance.

"Do you think I want them to die, you sanctimonious idiot? Are you even listening to me? I'm saying that it doesn't matter how much you want them to live, because the world is too complicated! You're denying the data! You want to do things that no one has ever done, and do them all at once which no one has even dreamed of doing. Not Dumbledore, not Salazar Slytherin, not the Peverell brothers, not even Merlin the bloody First Enchanter himself! The greatest wizards in the history of the world only barely attempted some tiny fraction of your insane fever dream! You want to rule the world and end death, good and fine, and you want to end poverty and sickness and make everyone equal and put goblins and other trash up on a pedestal and all that other fluffy nonsense, fine!" Draco was shouting, now. "But it is impossible! It is just impossible! To do any one of them was beyond anyone's power, even those who tried, much less all of it at once! And by trying to do it, you're going to burn down this world and everyone in it, and it is just beyond arrogant and stupid to look at the world and declare that you are going to change it so much and so fast, and we are all suffering because of that!"

Harry roared back at Draco, his voice larger than himself, as though it were echoing the cries of others, of legions, "I don't give a damn if it is impossible! I don't give a damn if no one has ever done it or tried it or dreamed it in the history of the world! 'Impossible' is a little word and a petty one - it's the word of small minds and small imaginations, and I reject it."

Draco opened his mouth to say something, but Harry continued over him, shouting now, white iron in his words and eyes and heart, a white glow suffusing him as a glow from his wand waxed brighter and brighter.

"We are standing on the brink - at the moment of crux between peril and paradise, Draco! We are caught at the edges of two singularities, held equipoise at their event horizons, and it is terrifying, but when they offer you the Ring you don't reject it with the word 'impossible!'"

Draco shouted back, lunging forward to stab a finger into Harry's chest: accusatory. "Not everything is possible in this world!"

And Harry replied, quietly, "Draco. There are more worlds than this one. We'll make one where we can save everybody. Impossible just means you haven't figured out how to cheat."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

JUPITER: Pauvres gens! Tu vas leur faire cadeau de la solitude et de la honte, tu vas arracher les étoffes dont je les avais couverts, et tu leur montreras soudain leur existence, leur obscène et fade existence, qui leur est donnée pour rien.

ORESTE: Pourquoi leur refuserais-je le désepoir qui est en moi, puisque c'est leur lot?

JUPITER: Qu'en feront-ils?

ORESTE: Ce qu'ils voudront: ils sont libres, et la vie humaine commence de l'autre côté du désespoir.

ZEUS: Poor people! Your gift to them will be a sad one; of loneliness and shame. You will tear

from their eyes the veils I had laid on them, and they will see their lives as they are, foul and

futile, a barren boon.

ORESTES Why, since it is their lot, should I deny them the despair I have in me?

ZEUS: What will they make of it?

ORESTES What they choose. They're free; and human life begins on the far side of despair.

-Les Mouches, Jean-Paul Sartre

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

April 30th, 1999

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

Now

Pain has an element of blank, and Harry suffered for some uncertain amount of time, twisting before Bellatrix Black's Cruciatus Curse. It was pain on another level - beyond the sort of suffering that should have been possible with mere nerves - a torture that transcended physicality. His very existence was in agony.

Eventually, it stopped, and Harry found that he was lying on the floor of the corridor some distance down from where he'd begun. They'd moved him. He was soaked in sweat and shaking, and his throat was hoarse from screams he hadn't even know he'd been making.

The other Bellatrix was casting spells, sealing them off from the Extension Establishment. She cast them so quickly and so fluidly that Harry thought that she might have been able to hold off every single one of his gathered allies, striking them down one by one as they attempted the corridor.

His torturer stood over him, leering, crazed. "Little dollies are dead. Your stupid slut of a mudblood is dead. I killed her. Your aurors are dead. And now you're going to tell me where the Dark Lord is, or we'll start killing everyone else."

Harry tried to calm his panting and sobbing. He separated it from himself, and closed his eyes. After a moment, he opened them again, fixing them on the witch. "I'm sorry. I want you to know that. What happened to you should never happen to anyone, and I am so sorry that it did. We're going to get you help."

All amusement vanished from her face. She looked bored, and contemptuous, staring at him with eyes of darkness and blood. "There is no help, little billy. And you have no way out."

Harry closed his eyes again. "I know. I thought, maybe… I thought others could do this with me. That maybe they could take my place if they worked together. That I could be free. And maybe that will happen, someday. But sometimes a person gets lucky enough, or unlucky enough, to be put on the spot. To be the crux of things. And I had a friend, once - a phoenix - who taught me never to shy away from that."

"You talk like him," said the other Bellatrix. The one standing over Harry nodded, a look of fascination on her face. "But you are a wretched little homunculus, and now you'll learn a lesson."

"Impossible little billy boy," sneered the witch standing over Harry, and leaned forward, her wand pointing at his chest. "Time time time."

"I'm sorry, Bellatrix. I don't accept this," Harry said.

Blood blossomed from her chest, and Bellatrix Black gurgled. Her remaining eye opened wide, and her mouth worked open and shut.

The Cloak of Invisibility slid to the floor.

And Hermione Granger pulled her fist from Bellatrix's back, blood splattering her determined face.

"No!" shrieked the other Bellatrix, whirling and raising her wand, but a hail of curses from behind Hermione cut her down and cut off her scream. Stunned and bound and silenced and paralyzed, Bellatrix Black toppled over, her face still distorted in shock and fury and hatred.

"I'm sorry, Bellatrix. I found a way to cheat," said Harry.

"Mr. Potter!" called Pip from the corner at the end of the corridor. He was staggering forward, seemingly about to faint, but was supported by J.C. Kraeme. She had his arm around her neck and was holding him up. They trailed behind Hyori, who had her wand up and still fixed on the two Bellatrixen as she strode down the hall. Her face was grim - but less grim than usual.

Hermione glanced over at him and nodded at him as she knelt next to the witch she'd felled. He could see her wand sticking out of her belt, but it was broken. The last two inches were missing, exposing the raw reddish strand of dragon heartstring at the core. Useless.

Harry winced as she plunged two fingers into her left arm, and yanked free her spare wand. She set it to Bellatrix's chest, and began casting, working to heal the wound she'd caused and save the life of the insane villain.

He sighed, lowering his head to the ground. He just lay there, still, for a moment, and smiled. He smiled in spite of everything.

Out of sight, down where the north and south corridor met, he knew that the entrance to the Tower stood, unharmed. A golden oval, bright-shining and standing with impossible solidity.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

JUPITER: Rentre dans la nature, fils dénaturé: connais ta faute, abhorre-la, arrache-la de toi comme une dent cariée et puante. Ou redoute que la mer ne se retire devant toi, que les sources ne se tarissent sur ton chemin, que les pierres et les rochers ne roulent hors de ta route et que la terre ne s'effrite sous tes pas.

ORESTE: Qu'elle s'effrite! Que les rochers me condamnent et que les plantes se fanent sur mon passage: tout ton univers ne suffira pas à me donner tort. Tu es le roi de Dieux, Jupiter, le roi des pierres et des étoiles, le roi des vagues de la mer. Mais tu n'es pas le roi des hommes.

JUPITER: Je ne suis pas ton roi, larve impudente. Qui donc t'a créé?

ORESTE: Toi. Mais il ne faillait pas me créer libre.

ZEUS: Know your sin, abhor it, and tear it from you as one tears out a rotten, noisome tooth. Or else — beware lest the very seas shrink back at your approach, springs dry up when you pass by, stones and rocks roll from your path, and the earth crumbles under your feet.

ORESTES: Let it crumble! Let the rocks revile me, and flowers wilt at my coming. Your whole

universe is not enough to prove me wrong. You are the king of gods, king of stones and stars,

king of the waves of the sea. But you are not the king of man.

ZEUS: Impudent spawn! So I am not your king? Who, then, made you?

ORESTES: You. But you blundered; you should not have made me free.

-Les Mouches, Jean-Paul Sartre

Chapter 45: Bonus, Draco

Pursuant to an agreement, I grant and confirm to Armand Malfoi the Vale of Haxburn Downs, with the Manor of Haxburn, and the Chapel of Haxburn, &c of the gift of Osmundus Æþelindus, Earl of Haxburn. I commend it to the Use of the selfsame Armand Malfoi with all good thanks for his Service for he has ever been a True Friend and Loyal Servant of my House, and I know it shall ever be So, and I do charge Armand Malfoi with the good maintenance and safekeep of the Treasury of the South West with all my Trust.

Grant of Lord-Enchanter Assurence de Chute, two years before his untimely death

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Malfoy Manor, Wiltshire, England

February 12th, 1997

A year and ago

"Put the samovar on," Draco said, gesturing at the tapered silver device and glancing at Gregory. Three domovoi were visiting that evening, and they tended to be particular about such niceties. It was probably part of their unrelenting feelings of inferiority towards the British, as though Merlin's heirs were to blame for their position on top of the Confederation or their legacy of powerful magic. The Russians always wanted to be treated with every little courtesy, and bristled at any perceived slight.

Not that Draco would have it any other way. It was an easy lever to use, and required nothing of him but a bit of forethought. Everyone should be so pliable.

Gregory Goyle obliged, twisting one of the handles of the samovar. The device was an elegant piece, with two stylized dragon's heads protruding from the top. It began to heat itself with a quiet hiss. "What's the plan?"

"You bring them in, and then go and tag their brooms. The Thunderer has been spreading gold around, looking for ways to co-opt the Honourable. I want to know who's been helpful enough to be the point person for his emissaries," said Draco. "Once you've done that - and check out their people, see if there's any opportunities there - then you'll join us and play the heavy."

Draco paused, then spoke to the air, curtly. "Dobby."

Barely a breath passed before the elf appeared, stepping out from behind a curtain. It was rude to apparate into the middle of a room, of course… proper house elf etiquette required a furtive entrance. The bedraggled little creature's bony face was pained with anxiety. "Master?"

"Pack for a journey. Mother and I, both. Cold weather. Riding, formal blacks, formal greens, and lounging," Draco commanded. "I'll want to be ready to go by the time my meeting tonight is concluded." He turned away, gesturing dismissively.

"Yes, Master," said Dobby, eyes wide. He gently stepped back behind the curtain.

"Will Carrow be here for the meeting?" Gregory asked, looking uncomfortable.

"Yes," said Draco, giving Gregory a direct and cold look. What of it?, his face said.

"Fine," said Gregory. Nothing more. He busied himself with arranging the furniture appropriately. He removed the two light wooden chairs from the room, levitating them out and replacing them with heavier armchairs. There were five of these: two set in close pairs and one separate, near the fire. Draco would take the single chair, of course, and allow the visitors to choose their own seats.

How the Russians arranged themselves would be valuable information. If two sat and one stood nearby, it would show that they were choosing solidarity in some respect - usually indicating nervousness or conscious opposition. If all three sat immediately, it would show comfort and ease, suggesting Draco could easily advance the relationship by taking the domovoi into his confidence that very evening. If there was hesitation, the process and order in which they sat could be observed: who was the leader, who deferred to others, and so on.

Poor little domovoi, coming to Malfoy Manor.

They were necessary for the future, though - not just entertainment. Draco had a significant power base in Britain and many admirers abroad - the international subscriptions to Unbreakable Honour were almost equal to the domestic numbers - but he'd never be a credible player on the world stage until he had some firmer connections with some of the globe's more reliable leaders. Voters were all well and good, but if you wanted iron in the glove, you needed some of the better sort on your side. You needed some tyrants.

There was a creak in the hallway outside, and Draco froze. Gregory snatched his wand up, his face hard.

"It's I," came the smooth voice of Amycus Carrow, "your Uncle Amycus."

"Come," said Draco.

The door opened, and Amycus Carrow entered. Tall and gaunt, the spymaster of the Honourable and old ally of the Malfoys was wearing black robes with shiny buttons, fastened tight up to his chin. The dark shadow of some scraggly whiskers were visible on his upper lip, and his hair was clipped very short.

"Draco, my boy," said Carrow. "So good to see you." His eyes flickered over the length of Draco's body, the way they always did - a possessive and lingering look. "Nacreous liver," he murmured, bizarrely and almost inaudibly. He seemed almost hungry.

"Hullo, Mr. Carrow," said Gregory, just a touch too loudly. He put a smile on his face as a shield.

Carrow started slightly, as though he hadn't realized Gregory was there, and swiveled his head to glance at the other man. "Gregory," he said in acknowledgment.

As usual, Draco was forced to admire the performance of Mad-Eye Moody. It wasn't simply the perfection of the acting, although that was so masterful that not even Amycus Carrow's nieces suspected the subterfuge (it helped that they were never permitted to spend much time with him, or to ever be alone with him: the uneasy parent's usual precaution against a "acrohandula"). No, the true magnificence of the performance was that Draco knew - he knew - that Moody was putting on this perfect imitation of Carrow at the same time as he played the part of Draco's spymaster while also watching out for Harry Potter's interests and remaining constantly vigilant of immediate threats. It was the virtuoso exhibition of a masterful fanatic.

"Was your excursion useful, Amycus?" Draco asked.

Moody - no, it was impossible to think of him as anything other than Amycus Carrow - Carrow pursed his lips. "Yes… I think so. You are the only one who can credibly promise such gifts to the Thai. They won't step out ahead of China, for fear of being left alone in the cold, but they will drag their feet as much as they may. The Ten Thousand are never quick on the stick, but I don't believe we need to worry about them joining the ranks of our enemies, any time soon."

The dragon's heads on top of the samovar opened their mouths, hissing twin streams of steam. Their eyes glowed a dull red.

Draco walked to one of the room's tall windows, and stood there for a moment, looking out at the night. He could see one of the towers of The Declaration of Intent, and it was a sharp reminder of the importance of the stewardship of assets.

"We will give them nothing they can use - ideas of promise, but no application. Dead ends," said Draco. "A taste of power, but nothing to tip our hand or upset the balance in the Ten Thousand."

"They aren't fools, my boy," said Carrow. "They won't be so easily misled. If a bitch will bear no pups, you don't just cut its throat… you also give your elf a lesson with the knife."

Draco thought of Dobby, and smirked. "If an elf is left so poorly trained, then there's no one to blame but yourself." He reversed Moody's metaphor, making it more to his liking: "We will throw a treat to our foreign friends. The Thais, the Russians, those Americans… old allies and new, they'll learn the potential power of joining us. We have people within the Tower and in the Department of Mysteries to assist."

"Such as Umbridge won't get you what we need," said Carrow, stroking his chin.

"Stolen secrets won't be the sole bait. There will also be simple advancements harvested from the Muggles. There is remarkable power in these techniques… power that will astonish even you, Amycus," said Draco, turning to the side and regarding Carrow again. "The principles of Mendel can reshape the flesh of beasts in a fashion more safe and more stable than even the feats of the fabled sarkamancers of the Eleusinian Mysteries. You think it is an accident that Loony Lovegood is meddling with Devil's Snare? The methods behind her madness are a coin for us, too." He snapped his fingers. "And we will also buy trust with deceit. Already and at this very moment, I am acting to set up a rival to the Honourable - a rival that will conspicuously fail, and in the process cost our erstwhile allies any investment they might make."

"Your lovely mother," said Amycus, nodding slowly.

"Taking a meeting - she is considerably enthused about the project. I believe it amuses her to hand-craft a rival. Traps made of people are an elegant thing."

"I would have been able to assist in this, had I known ahead of time, my boy." Carrow folded his hands in front of himself, tilting his head slightly to the side. His right eye twitched. "A mistake."

Draco's expression became cold, and his eyes narrowed.

Carrow stared back, unblinking.

There was a long pause. Then Draco drew a breath, and spoke with cold care. "You presume too much, Carrow."

Gregory stood up a little straighter, and squared his shoulders; a subtle and appreciated signal.

Draco turned to face Carrow, and brought his palms together in front of himself. He drew them apart across his chest, and as they parted, his father's cane appeared in the gap, growing as Draco spread his hands, until the Lord Malfoy could grasp the snake-headed silver handle and bring the other end down to the floorboards with a sharp crack.

Draco raised his voice, beginning loudly, all thunder and lightning "I am Draco Malfoy, and I… I..."

His voice trailed off. Draco lowered his gaze. He fell silent. He let his shoulders slump slightly, as though the wind had been taken from his sails. He stood like that, and held it. Waited.

"Lord Malfoy?" asked Gregory, hesitantly.

"No," said Draco.

Gregory drew a sharp breath.

Draco raised his eyes again, glancing at Gregory. "No," he said again. "This is too important. It is too important for grandstanding."

Then he met Carrow's eyes with a steady gaze, and his voice was quiet. "No speeches, no grandeur, no orders. I tell you here tonight, Amycus Carrow, that this is the sticking point for a hundred generations of wizardkind. If we fail, then the world will be a darker and sadder place." Draco thought of a silver light he'd once seen… a pure glow that had overturned so many lies with its very existence, filling him with such an argent awe that it changed his world in a heartbeat. He imagined that light gone forever, and let that sorrow fill his voice. "If we fail - if we let one trick slip by or fall short by an ounce of wit, then our world will become a Muggle-made thing of immortal monsters. We are confronting an existential threat: a looming power that might not only end us, but end everything we hold dear."

He shook his head. "So no threats and no foolishness. If you don't have the mettle to hold to your place and do your part, even when it harms your pride, well - go, and may your chains sit lightly upon you." He raised his cane - a mere symbol and a powerless prop, but wasn't persuasion the mightiest thing of all? - and he pointed it at Carrow. "But if you have honour, and you're with us… then you are with us, and you will heed your place."

Apophasis.

Before he'd even finished speaking, Carrow had fallen to one knee. "I can offer nothing but my apology and my fealty, Lord Malfoy."

Gregory looked as satisfied as the kneazle that caught the cracklebit. He crossed his arms, and a smile lurked at the corner of his mouth. He looked a foot taller. He looked like faith fulfilled.

"Master," said Dobby, emerging from behind a different curtain. "Your visitors are here."

"Let them in," said Draco, without taking his gaze off of Carrow. Dobby disappeared back behind the curtain once more. Draco lowered his cane. "Goyle, go meet them."

Goyle left, his face revealing barely-disguised triumph. The story of this moment would travel. Draco smiled.

Carrow and Draco were alone. There was only the quiet hiss of steam, rising dangerously from twin dragon heads, to keep them company.

"Bah," said Carrow, rising off of his knee and standing up again. He snatched out his wand and waggled it, almost too fast to follow, the the warm crackle of wards settled on around them. Privacy screens, above and beyond the ones that already layered the Manor.

Draco didn't say anything - didn't rub it in. There was no need.

"Try that again, Malfoy," he said, glowering, "and you will get a rather different reaction. Goyle will be spreading the story of how you lost an ear, instead."

Draco watched him coolly. "And damage everything we've been building? You have more discipline than that."

"Maybe. But also too much discipline to be afraid to upset the applecart, if need be," replied Carrow.

"Before you do, be quite certain it's worth it. One only gets one chance at ruining plans like these."

"Plans like these? Your mother is setting up some small circle of idiots to take a fall, sucking some Cappadocian money with them as they go, eh? Helping build up the Honourable to draw in all the enemy?" said Carrow. He stabbed a finger at Draco. "Or is it a cover for your own efforts to set up an independent base of power?"

"I'm not above a fall-back plan, Mad-eye," said Draco, "because I am not an idiot. If something happens to Harry, or he goes too far, or anything else… well, I don't intend to wager everything on one game of pitch-and-toss. But my fall-back lies in the Honourable: they are my 'independent' base of power, if need be, not some momentary troop of patsies. That is why the Honourable are loyal to me, personally. Harry knows that. You know that. And you both understand it, too, I think." He fixed Carrow with a harsh look. "Don't pretend to purity. I know you have your own private plans."

Not that he knew, really, but there could not be a safer assumption.

"There's a difference between preparation and betrayal," said Carrow, in a most un-Carrow-like growl. "Which are you at, I wonder?"

"Continue to wonder," pronounced Draco, curtly.

"Aye," said Carrow, slowly. "Well. You may believe you can bludger Potter in the back, if you get the opportunity. And maybe you're right. He's clever, but soft. He trusts you. But I don't."

Carrow gave Draco a hard stare, and his very face was a reminder of his capacity for subterfuge. "Be careful thinking you can play a deeper game than me, boy. Many have tried... and gotten no deeper than six feet."

"Lord Draco Malfoy," said Gregory, opening the door across the room, "of the Noble and Most Ancient House of Malfoy, Britain's last and best defender of the honour of wizardkind and the fate of magic."

Draco turned to regard the door, cane in hand, and his face slid into a courteous smile of welcome. Three men with hard faces but indifferent grooming stepped into the room ahead of Gregory. They had the weighty air of importance. One of them wore a brooch of emeralds-and-alicorn, while another openly carried an old wand of the Slavic style, two feet long and bladed. They all wore the red woollen cloaks of Russian domovoi: the decision-makers of one of the great peoples in the wizarding world, no less magisterial than the Wizengamot. These were men who had held lives in their hands, who had scrutinized their subjects down to the curve of their soul, who had begun and ended wars as they saw fit.

Now they were come to Malfoy Manor.

Carrow and Goyle walked over to stand beside Draco. Draco's smile broadened.

"Please, gentlemen," he said. "Sit wherever you like."

Chapter 47: The Thing with Wings

KARL: You think you are safe here, in your village utopia? War is upon us! Hear the sound of drums. The enemy approaches in scant minutes, and our hourglass flows so quickly... witness the last of the time! Lords and ladies… I beseech you! Wake up and attend to your own hour of doom! Flee!

ERIN: We hear. We understand. But we will not run. We will not abandon Sontag.

"The Last Days of Exses O'Bruinan," by S. Leigh, as staged in the 1979 London production.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

May 18th, 1999

One day later

Draco's office in the Tower was in the rear of the complex, where it had been expanded. He had originally been situated near Material Methods. It might have been quiet there at the moment, with the goblins all shut up and withdrawn into Curd and Ackle, off doing gobliney things (presumably comparing ear length or bathing in rubies). But as soon as the dodgy little blokes were back to work, hammering out more absurdly large golden gloves, then that area would become intolerable: unfortunate smells, clamorous noise, and a horde of chest-high half-elves swarming underfoot in the corridor.

Now he was comfortably ensconced next to the new offices of the Vision Verge, instead. They were almost all wizards and witches, except for the one centaur, and they mostly did quiet things involving lenses and the like. It was uninteresting work - what possible use was there for the tiny Protean-Charmed little toggles they were making? - but also a peaceful little corner of the oft-bustling Tower.

Dearest Mother, he wrote, leaning over the parchment on the desk in front of him.

All is going well - better than we could have hoped. There are plans to reorganize the way the Tower operates, now that a new Receiving Room will be built to accommodate the Ten Thousand. That has meant a second Terminus to be in charge, and a second command structure for it, and now the whole question of who reports to whom has been upended. The Westphalians are all in a clamour about the new addition, as well, and are arguing that the Americas should also have their own Receiving Room. If they win, then simple pride will oblige the construction of a fourth Room for the Free States, Nigeria, and any other African states that join.

In fact, I believe that the Tower will become a proxy body for the Confederation, which will soon mean, of course, that it will become subject to votes from that body. Potter is a soft touch, and he won't be able to flout the Confederation forever without the excuse of the Independent opposition. That will be an opportunity for many, including us. Good fortune floats into our hand like a ripe dirigible plum.

Draco continued in this vein for some length, setting forth his pretended expectations with just enough vagueness to appear plausible. He laid out a vision of a potential path to power within the Tower - and more importantly, made sure that this vision was transferable: a blueprint for others to follow, as well.

When he was done, he took a parchment razor and notched the lower-left corner of the first page twice, then folded and sealed the packet. Draco would send it to his mother, and she'd know it was meant for others to see. It would be "stolen," and reinforce his efforts at tempting a few choice individuals into the fold.

There was a loud knock at his office door.

Draco looked up, irritated at the interruption. He glanced at the big watch on the wall. He was expecting his "spy" and ally Dolores Umbridge at ten o'clock, but he'd expected to have time to write a genuine dispatch to his mother in addition to the fake one. They'd built something special over these past years with their Honourable, and he had no intentions of letting it - or their relationship with each other - decay. "Who is it?" he asked, curtly.

"There are some who call me… Tim," said a voice from the other side of the door.

"Come in, Longbottom," Draco said, sighing in annoyance.

Neville opened the door, glancing around the room as he stepped inside. At some point in the years since he and Draco had first boarded the Hogwarts Express, Neville had grown tall and handsome. He was a bit gawky, but with an obvious strength in his wiry frame. His eyes were bright and his smile was wide and he was utterly intolerable.

"Harry wanted to know if you had a minute," Neville said. He squinted at a statue in the corner - a beautiful sculpture in gold of a fat-bodied cobra with numerous heads, coils piling up beneath it and a single broad hood loomed behind its heads.

"Fine," said Draco, checking the wall-watch again. He dropped the cover over the inkwell built into his desk and cleared the parchments to one side. He included the fake dispatch among them. He'd send it later.

Neville jerked a thumb in the direction of the statue. "That's new."

"It's from Thailand," said Draco, turning to regard it. "Not a real beast. 'Ananta Shesha,' a fanciful notion of the Muggles… They say that it holds the entire world on its hood."

Neville regarded it closely. There were tiny scales pricked into its surface, and each tiny snake-head wore a delicate crown. "So he's trod down by everyone else, despite all his crowns?" he asked, lightly.

Draco ignored the jab for a moment. He adjusted his robes as he walked around the desk, and he kept his voice mild as he replied, "One day, they say he will uncoil."

Neville scowled as the Slytherin stepped past him and out into the corridor. Draco turned to give him a level look, and spoke over his shoulder, "And then, he'll be all that's left." Draco smiled coolly. "Ananta Shesha: 'that which remains.' "

Not his best work… but then, it was only Neville, who spent most of his day wallowing with Muggles and play-fighting with them.

Draco walked briskly down the corridor, past the Verge, and along the hallway squeezed between the Conjuration Conjunction and Extension Establishment, the latter filled with annoyed people snapping at each other irritably. There had been serious malfunctions in the latest slicebox prototypes. They were intended for the creation of a second pocket world, which would also be put into orbit out past the sky, but they'd been rupturing instead. One researcher had nearly been killed by an accidental backlash that had bisected her at the waist.

He turned left, moving past the entrance to Material Methods, and then pushed open the door to the meeting room, striding on inside. It's important not just to look like you know what's going on, but to appear to actually be in command of it, his father had used to say.

There were a few people in the meeting room with Harry. A couple of aurors, Percy Weasley, and Cedric Diggory. No Bones and no Mad-Eye… nothing about the Tower or politics or anything foreign. Probably government...

He considered likely possibilities as quickly as possible as he nodded to those sitting at the table and walked over, past the aurors.

Was this about his mother? No, they'd leave that alone, no matter what. They knew better than to get between Draco and his family. They knew he was a Malfoy above all.

Had one of his minions gotten out of hand? Draco did an inventory of the likely suspects - the lowbrow pawns who'd run most of Knockturn Alley. Gem and his people were in Howard Prison for another three months… Laura Lock and Tallow Enser were still in hiding in Kent and unwilling to come out. That left Jean-Luc Bigby and Mortimer Kainen. They'd been kipps by trade six years ago, collecting loans and insurance. Had they gone back to that and gotten picked up after hexing the wrong person?

Was this more personal? Had they started getting information from Bellatrix, finally - penetrating the unfathomable protection of her insanity?

"Hello, Harry," Draco said, standing behind an empty seat. He rested his hands on it. He waited just a fraction of a second before turning to the other two, saying, "Diggory. Weasley." A gentle reminder of the order of things. "What are we on about this morning?"

"Just the usual, Malfoy," said Cedric, with his customary badly-disguised air of scorn. He'd had difficulty accepting the new reality in the Tower: Draco as ally and not defeated enemy.

Draco smiled a knowing smile, and pulled his chair out. But he didn't sit down, pausing.

There was something wrong.

Draco didn't know what it was, but he knew there was something wrong. He glanced from face to face, again. He couldn't quite put his finger on it, but he felt the disquiet in his guts.

What is it? Is it Mother, after all? No, Harry would tell me in private first, if that were it. Was it a misunderstanding - the uncovering of a "plot" to overthrow Harry, and it's been misunderstood?

He could see it, now, all of a sudden, as they looked back at him. It was their expressions. Harry and Diggory and Weasley all seemed to have their attention somewhere else. Not as though they weren't paying attention or anything so obvious - but rather, it was as though they were distracted by a noise or presence that he couldn't see. It was subtle… but then, Draco's tutor in the social graces, Master DeCampo, had always said that manipulation was the most delicate dance of all. These were three people struggling with their guilt. He could see it.

Why do they feel guilty?

"I think -" Draco began, but he could already feel the presence of the aurors close behind him.

A wand jabbed into his back.

Draco smirked, despite the roiling of his stomach. Did Harry seriously think I've never considered the possibility of betrayal? "There are only three certainties: death, betrayal, and hag's teeth." He'd personally made a portkey to his own office within the Tower. Portkeys couldn't take him outside the facility, but they could travel within its bounds - to a prepared escape cache.

"This is a mistake, Potter," he said. He considered the appropriate bon mot to leave in his wake, and fixed Harry's eyes with his own. Harry looked conflicted, his face uncertain. Uncommitted. Ultimately, not enough will to carry this out. Draco felt more confidence at the thought. This might actually be a good thing.

A hand rested lightly on his shoulder from behind, from someone unseen.

"Egeustimentis," he heard.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

After the necessary adjustments, they all sat down together. The Master took Harry's usual seat. They began to discuss what seemed to be the next step.

"Trying to ambush Mad-Eye," said Draco, shaking his head. "It sounds almost like a… like something that is untrue by its very nature."

"A contradiction in terms?" suggested Cedric.

"A paradox?" offered Harry.

Draco nodded at Harry. "A paradox. Like burning water. Or a lucky elf." He shook his head. " 'An ambushed Moody.' Impossible."

"Well, we've hit critical mass, I think," said Harry. "We have enough people to do it, but not so many people that we've been found out. Most of the aurors on shift yesterday and during the night, and everyone on shift today - and now Draco. If we act now, we might even keep it from getting messy." He looked hopefully over at the Master.

"Yes," Meldh said, nodding gently. "The changes I have made are not… subtle. The Lethe Touch takes centuries to master, but even my skill is not enough to disguise such a change in, ah, priorities, shall we say?"

Draco nodded in agreement, as well. "I knew something was different when I walked into the meeting. And there's no sense in wasting an asset that might help the Master, later. You're right, we should act immediately."

Harry leaned forward, using one hand to brush the end of his ponytail back over his shoulder. "Is there any risk the Lethe Touch will wear off?" he asked Meldh. "If it has a time limit, we should make sure to set up a schedule - maybe a system to keep an eye on each other." He paused, thoughtfully, and wagged a finger at his Master. "If we're going to help you, you're going to need to start telling us things about what you want and your assets."

Meldh raised an eyebrow. He leaned forward and folded his arms on the table in front of him. He had a mild look on his face - amused curiosity, as though he were looking at children. "Oh?"

"Are you fishing for information, Harry?" asked Cedric, frowning suspiciously.

"Well, yes," said Harry, contemplatively. "It's interesting. I suppose I'd always assumed that mind magic like Imperius would come with an underlying change in personality and methodology. Maybe I've been making comparisons to Muggle techniques that don't serve - things like brainwashing. Instead, it's more like Muggle politics than anything else… the dark side of rationality, where ideas don't have inherent value, but only matter as… as... " He made a gesture. "As soldiers. In politics, whether or not an idea or theory reflects reality is less important than whether it helps or hurts my team."

Meldh's face darkened. He rose from his seat, slowly. "How can you speak this way? How have you defeated the Touch?"

Harry shook his head. "It's not what you think. I serve you above all else, Master Meldh. But you didn't lobotomize me. I'm capable of introspection - I can recognize that the change to my priorities wasn't predicated on rational assessment of the situation." He grinned, good-naturedly. "More knowledge is better, even about yourself. You'd be amazed how many times I've had to talk about this -"

"Lecture about this," Cedric put in, sighing.

"- but it's true," Harry continued, unperturbed. "There's no danger to knowing how your own mind works, including all of the biases that damage your ability to make rational decisions. We're incredibly biased towards acting according to your instructions, Master, and it wouldn't serve you to pretend that's not so."

"It would be less creepy, Harry, if you would just make your peace with it," said Draco, frowning. "Accept that this is the way it is, and don't overthink it."

"No, no," said Harry, quickly. "That's just it! You're conflating the idea of resisting the change in our minds with the idea of understanding it."

"This is not useful," said Meldh, quietly. He'd become mild again, apparently accepting Harry's explanation, and lowered himself back into his seat. "We will finish planning, so that we eliminate all threats. Then we will take the time to prepare our moves for the future… what pieces we keep and what pieces we sacrifice. We will adjust our strategy, so we can move towards my chosen endgame - not your madness of healing Muggles and throwing things into the sky. Magic must have its end."

Harry looked momentarily flummoxed, opening and closing his mouth a few times. Draco smirked, watching. Eventually, Harry found words again, frowning. "Yes, sir." His frown became surprise, as though he'd intended to say something else.

Draco turned his attention back to the Master. "He is due to come in today at some point for an intrusion attempt, since it's an even-numbered day. I suggest we prepare a fake repeater in the clinic, and ask him for help."

"There have been a few people who have been unhappy with their rejuvenation who have tried to convince us to do the process again," Cedric explained. "It's against policy, since it's too time-consuming and it takes time away from others. If a healer is rejuvenating someone for the second or third time, that means there's someone else in actual need of rejuvenation who has to wait in suspension. We had three French wizards who caused a problem about this, a couple of years ago, and backed up the queue so badly that several people came very near to dying. We keep a sharp eye on répéteurs ever since."

"Moody has prepared for this sort of thing," said Harry. "I know for a fact. One of his jobs is to be paranoid about everyone." He stabbed a finger onto the surface of the table. "Even me." He turned to Draco. "One level won't be enough. We need levels and levels if we want to have any hope, here."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Alastair Moody was waiting until just before midnight. People got sloppy at night - forgot to check their corners, lost track of everyone in the room, and other laxness. He hadn't done a night intrusion on the Tower in months. By that time, they'd be wondering if he'd already managed to get in… they'd start double-checking the patients already in the clinic and verifying the identity of everyone in the halls. Added to their fatigue, it might be the edge he needed to get to Harry and "assassinate" him.

He smiled to himself as he checked the Glenwallace Traps on the doorframes of his house. This was going to be a fun one.

It helped that he was in a good body. A tall and healthy man with a dark complexion and brown eyes - nondescript but usefully vital. There was a lot to be said for the usefulness of sheer physical health when it came to break-ins, although the stealth value of a small child or an obese man wasn't to be shunned.

A small bell rang twice, and Moody frowned. Owl in the hutch. He checked the front door and the windows, and then went to the hutch. It was carrying nothing but parchment, so he opened the swivel-door barrier and let the owl through, and plucked the message free.

REPEATER IN THE CLINIC. WE NEED A QUIET REMOVAL AND TO MAKE SURE THIS DOESN'T HAPPEN AGAIN. APPLY PERSUASION.

It was signed by Malfoy.

A trick? A trap? Alastair knew where at least 75% of Malfoy's little gang were, and they were almost all neutralized. Assuming he could be wrong by as much as a fifth, and that Malfoy might have gotten leverage over some of the mid-level aurors - maybe a Terminus on duty - or maybe Malfoy himself had been suborned by a larger operation or a powerful individual, maybe the Three. Or just an attempt to curry favor. Or rather, more subtle: an attempt to appear as though he were currying favor, so as to be taking an obvious hopeless action in a safe way while putting forth another plan.

Might also be the Chinese or Americans, making a try now that they had their foot in the door. He wouldn't put it past that lousy little Hig, who was all helpful and sweet now that the Westphalians had what they wanted.

It was also just barely possible that there was no ulterior motive to the situation or message. He chuckled out loud at the thought.

Alastair snatched some leaves of parchment from the writing desk near the hutch and wrote three terse messages in his crooked and crabbed hand, ordering a change in the shift commanders at the RCP and the Ministry, and sending a further letter to a cold-drop. Unlikely Malfoy or anyone else could have sway enough to manage every single shift commander. He sealed them with a hasty Verification Charm to match his wand, and sent them on their way.

He checked the Glenwallace Traps again, and the other Dark Detectors while he was at it. Then Alastair pulled on his gear and checked it over. He studied his appearance in the glass for a long moment, but he looked safely ordinary.

The safest way would be to Apparate to the Ministry and then take a secure Flue, but they'd be expecting that and it would, ironically, make him more identifiable. No, as so often, the best way was the more direct and fastest. A Safety Stick.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

It had looked wrong, right from the start.

Alastair walked into the clinic from the Receiving Room to find a repeater, all right - someone with the unblemished skin and youth of the rejuvenated. He was arguing in the middle of the clinic with a healer, who was calmly trying to redirect the repeater back into a cubicle.

But there were also seven aurors.

There was not any reason for there to be seven aurors. That was far too many. The three on shift here would have been sufficient, and an additional one from the Receiving Room would have been an abundance of caution. Sending four aurors in as reinforcement for a minor difficulty like this wasn't just a waste of resources: it would actually cause the very problem that they tried to avoid when repeaters showed up. Repeaters needed to be soothed, reassured, and sent on their way without a fuss.

Protocol was well-known. More than that, it was just common sense. And these weren't new aurors to the Tower, either, he noticed. They were old hands; people with experience, and no known ties to any other power that he knew. But here they were, where they shouldn't be, all standing in bunches.

Time to address the likelihood that this was a Malfoy trap for him (or a trap by someone else).

Alastair backed out of the clinic and turned to the auror standing farther down the corridor, the one he'd just passed. "Pirrip!"

The idiot turned. "Sir?" He'd just cleared Alastair mere moments ago, exchanging passwords.

"Go tell Harry that there's something very suspicious with the repeater in the clinic. Then come back at speed. Bring another hand with you - someone with battle experience," Alastair barked, sharply. He waited just long enough to see Pirrip on the jump, then turned and strode back into the clinic.

But scarcely was he inside before he heard a scream. He whirled to see that Pirrip hadn't even made it out of sight down the corridor - the young auror was down, thrashing on the ground. Gutclench Curse or something similar.

Almost without thinking, Alastair sidestepped to the right, and without a pause charged into motion, out of the clinic. Behind him, he could hear voices shouting and spells being cast. Not all focused on him - whatever this was, he still had allies. He barely thought about his reactions as he raised the purplish light of Azarian Fire behind him, throwing himself to the side once he was clear of the doorway to the clinic. The Fire erupted behind him with a rush of smoke, and he took the opportunity to crouch low and lean back around the doorway, snatching at the goblin-silver door just to one side. A spray of Bertram Bolts sizzled through the air over his head as he hauled at the door, and it smoothly slid into place.

He needed to get to Harry. Alastair took off at a dead run.

He didn't pause over Pirrip, not even breaking stride as he sprinted down the corridor over the lad. He spared a look to his right as he went past the entrance, but he could already see that the Receiving Room aurors had sent two of their number to assist him (traitors to stab him in the back? No, Madagascar and Nimue hated each other, that hate was more reliable than most things) and so he could rely on the alert being raised.

Down past the Advancement Agency, still sprinting, plucking a potion from his belt with his free hand and dropping it behind him, Alastair cursed. Whoever was behind this was causing chaos, but how could they think they'd win? That they'd get control of the Tower - they didn't even know what the Tower really was, or what happened here. Did they think to learn the "special webs" that made "Tower Transfiguration" possible here? Had they figured out the Stone… were they just trying to steal that? Moody hoped that Harry had his wits about him, and that he'd put on one of the decoy gloves as soon as he was threatened. The decoys each had a fragment of an ancient and ruined cup embedded in their palm, where the Stone went in the real glove - if anything was stolen, let it be one of them.

But it was much worse than he thought. Charging around the corner, taking the turn at a momentary crouch, wand raised, he saw that they'd already gotten to Harry oh Merlin oh no -

Harry was on the ground, and a knife was buried in his chest. Blood was spreading around him.

- check behind, nothing, run forward, call for help, two bringing up the rear to watch your back -

There was so much blood already, was the boy already dead? His shoes were wrong. He had to be saved, he had to be saved, there was no one who could take his place, not really.

- move to the side, wand up, there's someone Disillusioned, see the shimmer, no bother with removal, wide-angle attack, get down -

He dropped into a crouch again and raised his wand to Vom Tag, reaching out with his mind. He focused his will into the necessary shape and pushed away from him the thought of a grandmother's eyes and sparkling blue lights. It was devilishly tricky to aim, but he just needed to get it out there and he felt with relief the rush of arctic wind as it swept in a torrent away from his fingers, ripe with cold.

He brought up more Azarian Fire in front of him almost in the same breath, but never took his eye off the corridor. The blur of distortion that was his enemy made a movement, redirecting his attack. A skillful turn. Foolish to do it so well, they revealed too much about their style. Possibly meant to tempt him into overconfidence.

- no time for this, no time no time, use the arch you can make it secret again later like the last time -

Alastair whipped three rapid-fire curses at his opponent, buying a half-second to reach into his robes. He felt the metal ring in its pocket, and snatched it free. Lunging to the side, he snapped his wand forward, shouting a curse powerful enough that his own ears ached from the pressure of its passage.

And he hurled a metal ring at his enemy, urging it to work. He needed it to work. He needed it to save Harry.

The Arch of Ulak Unconquered, the most perfect prison ever devised, swelled impossibly as it sailed through the air. Within moments it had ceased to be a thing of physical reality, and had become a force of nature, transforming from a slender metal ring into a burnished hoop the size of a man.

Alastair's foe was fast: he had time to try two full spells as the Arch flew at him. Both spells, a rush of wind and a blaze of fire, were swallowed by the Arch so thoroughly that they might never have existed. The Arch was a thing unyielding and unknowable - the last sanction of Alastair Moody, the reserve he retained against any betrayal.

And then the Arch dropped down around the enemy, and the enemy was gone. There was only the empty metal hoop of the Arch resting on the stone, and Alastair brandishing his wand, and the aurors on his heels, and a dying Harry Potter-Evans-Verres. Whose shoes were wrong.

Whose shoes were wrong.

Trap.

There was only a moment between the realization and unconsciousness, but that moment was long enough for Alastair to understand. A fake enemy. A fake Harry. A fake attack. Everyone was in on it. Everyone had betrayed him. Everything had gone wrong. And he had no more tricks left.

Constant vigila

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

After Moody was theirs, the two aurors took away Kraeme's body, still transfigured into the shape of Harry. On Meldh's instructions, they put it in the clinic for the moment, until arrangements could be made. The Arch was more difficult. Moody himself had to whisper arcane words to it before he could lift it, releasing Cedric from a prison so complete that the Head Auror had not even been aware of the passage of time.

Everyone took a moment to recover.

But only a moment.

"Now, then," said Meldh, turning to Harry. The Tower was blinking away tears, but with awkward shakes his his head that suggested he wasn't aware of it. "I believe now is an excellent time to visit a certain black box. There is a threat we need to address… and I think on a more permanent basis than you are willing to do."

Harry felt an ache within himself, but no conflict within his will. The new arrangement of his mind carried him forward, as inexorably as a satellite sailing through space, and he nodded readily.

It was time to visit Voldemort.

Chapter 48: Pithos

[The goblin warlord CRAD THE CALLOW and two ATTENDANTS enter, stage left. CRAD, a loathsome beast with a foaming mouth, wears filthy animal skins and a necklace of wizard teeth. His hands are covered in blood. His ATTENDANTS are dressed in similarly barbaric regalia, and each carries bright torches. They stand before ERIN and KARL, triumphant.]

CRAD: Look at the princess! Now that I, Crad, the revenging angel of goblinkind, has come to spill wizard blood… now she cowers! This is the price your people pay for their crimes. It is natural for vengeance to follow foul deeds, as one season follows another... and this is my harvest season… and your season of death!

ERIN: I am a noble witch of Britain, sir, and I do not cower. That is a thing for beasts.

KARL: [Boldly] And goblins.

CRAD: [Gnashes his teeth and jumps up and down, waving his arms.] Still you defy me, though this miserable village lies in ashes?! Though every beast lies dead, and even the flax smolders in the fields?!

KARL: We do.

ERIN: And so shall we ever. The choice between right and wrong is as clear as the difference between night and day. And if there were aught others to witness this, perhaps in some later day, then I would declare to them that they need only use their eyes to tell the difference between good and evil! And what seeing wizard, witnessing the ugliness and needless cruelty of evil, could fail to promise to seek the good of their own kind?

- "The Last Days of Exses O'Bruinan," by S. Leigh, as staged in the 1979 London production.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

May 18th, 1999

The same day

"Why did you keep this place a secret to so many, Mr. Potter?" asked Meldh, calmly. He glanced around the small room as they emerged from a nightmarish corridor of traps and wards and locks - including even a five-minute waiting period that considerably amused Meldh.

The room was still sparsely furnished. There were stacks of cassette tapes and several auto-players sitting in a thick mass of Lovegood Leaf. There was a small wooden stool, with a yellow legal pad and mechanical pencil set upon it.

There was a black box.

Harry didn't answer for a moment, glancing over at the box, which remained silent. He walked over to the auto-players instead, where a quiet voice was reading a book-on-tape aloud. Harry bent down and turned it off, and the recorded sentence was strangled mid-word: "His professions might be sincere; but in the situation where fortune had placed him, it was scarcely poss-"

"Mr. Potter?" prompted Meldh.

"This is the second Tower," Harry said. "Before this, there was another facility… one that was part of Hogwarts. There was… an attack. A powerful wizard who had been driven insane with grief. He said that he wanted us to bring back his child, but I think it was a form of suicide for him. He'd planned it - arranged for a message to be sent from the future to stop us from using Time-Turners to stop him. He killed Hermione. Killed her phoenix."

Harry sighed. "At that time, I'd transfigured Voldemort into a small stone, so that I didn't have to kill him. But during the attack, Hermione threw me to safety, and when I landed, I lost the ring. And it was then that I realized that if I'd been seriously hurt or killed… well, Voldemort could have awakened or been freed, with the Philosopher's Stone right at hand. Moody had warned me of this before, and we'd taken additional measures, but… well, that plan wasn't going to work. Of all the possible solutions to keeping hold of him, I'd been taking one of the riskiest possible. So I set to work finding a solution. It was easier than I'd thought… many wizards in the past had worked on transferring or creating consciousness in artificial environments, enough to be actually worrying. This form of mandrake, when properly prepared, holds his consciousness. But I knew that many people wouldn't share my ethics about going to such lengths - that they might prefer more lethal solutions."

"I see," mused Meldh. They both looked at the box for a moment, contemplatively. Voldemort remained silent.

"You are mistaken, though, Mr. Potter," Meldh added. "It was we who sent that message. We'd known the gentleman for some time, after he intruded on our meeting place. An early attempt at an intervention in your affairs. Ineffective, I'm afraid… but perhaps that's for the best, now that I consider the matter in hindsight."

Harry's eyes were closed, and he staggered to the side. He clutched for the wall but fell short, dropping to one knee. He gasped, "Killed Granville… so many people… sir, I can't… I'm sorry…"

Meldh shook his head and smiled kindly. He walked over to Harry and bent down, putting a comforting hand on the young man's back. "It's all right, just give it a moment. This is my fault, I'm afraid… I have changed very little in you. Just your… ah, there is no word. Just your telos. The most important things for you. So there is some conflict. But my alterations cannot be overcome. Fear not."

"Fear," said Voldemort, suddenly. Meldh turned his head sharply and stood up straight at the sound, but did not appear alarmed. As ever, his expression was pleasant. It suited the older man well.

"I am not aping you," continued the voice from the box in neutral male tones. "That is a suggestion."

Meldh didn't respond immediately. Instead, he walked closer, scrutinizing the black box. After a moment, he said, "I do not accept your suggestion, but thank you for it. You are Tom Riddle? Or is it the more recent name - Professor Quirrell - that you go by?"

"I have had many names," said Voldemort. "Please address me as best suits you."

"Very well, Lord Voldemort," said Meldh, smiling. "I am a visitor to the Tower. You may call me Meldh - an old word from my youth."

There was a pause, then Voldemort said, "Your implication is obvious. But that is not a credible lie. I will thank you not to insult my intelligence, Meldh, if we are to speak."

"Oh?" asked Meldh, raising his voice slightly to be heard over Harry's gasping sobs, as the young man struggled to control himself.

"While I do not know if my faculties have been affected by this prison, I am not yet a gibbering moron," said Voldemort. "Accordingly, I am not credulous enough to accept the existence of such antiquity without rather more proof than that. It is apparent that you have directly interceded to enforce your will on Mr. Potter in some manner. Such an intervention would come at some risk, no matter your abilities. If you took even the most miniscule of risks regularly, even only once in the span of each century, then it is not credible that you would be here, alive. Fate is fickle." The voice from the box formed an artificial chuckle. "On that, you may take my word."

"Interesting," said Meldh, pleasantly. He did not comment further, but tilted his head to one side. He lifted one palm and stretched it to the box, and whispered some words with syllables as harsh as knives.

After some time, Meldh lowered his palm and raised his eyebrows. "Ah. This box. There used to be three of these. I do not know if the others survive. But this is well. Destroying this one will ensure that, even if the others exist, they are useless for their other purposes." He smiled, gently. "Kári Orden would be amused to see one of her boxes used as a zoo." He leaned forward, reaching out his hand as though to touch the box. He stopped short, however, his palm held over the fine black surface. A whisper of red light flickered across the box's surface.

"You little tyrants have always been useful. You swirl like a whirlwind, drawing lore and devices into your chaotic storm. You kill off rivals, steal items of power, and break open hidden hoards. And eventually, thanks to a hero - and sometimes with the help of the Lethe Touch or the Ritual of Home or the Dustukhíascue - you and much of what you've gathered are destroyed." Meldh straightened back up, smiling again. "You do the world much good with your attempted evil."

Across the small room, Harry was gathering himself to his feet, finally. His face was reddened with emotion, and his hair had come loose across his shoulders. He looked as though he'd been to war.

"You are here to end me," said Voldemort.

"Oh, yes," said Meldh.

"Then I am in the most enjoyable position of advantage. All roads lead to my will. That has not been the case for some time," said Voldemort. "You will forgive me for taking some pleasure in the situation."

"Sir, he has cast a unique spell - a new version of the Horcrux spell," said Harry. His voice still sounded strained, but he was upright and trying as hard as possible to help. "If he is killed, or manages to kill himself, or even if he is simply returned to a human brain that the spell recognizes, then his spirit will be free to resurrect in another place. We developed a way to detect the Horcrux network and have destroyed many of them, but many others still remain… including at least one that is far beyond our means at the moment."

"My contingencies are numerous, laid over the course of many years and reinforced during the year of my return," said Voldemort. The bland voice conveyed a hint of mockery, somehow. "With the Goblet of Fire and the Resurrection Stone, two of the most potent artifacts still in existence, I have laid my traps."

Meldh nodded, smiling pleasantly, and glanced back at Harry. "Is that so, Mr. Potter?"

"No, sir. As far as I can tell, Voldemort never had access to the Goblet of Fire, despite what he says," Harry said, slowly. Voldemort made no reply or contradiction. "It is locked away in the Department of Mysteries… they consider it Cadmean Class: too dangerous to use or research. It was kept in a vault that is inside of some sort of magical lake or pond or something - some security to put it beyond everyone's reach without the Line of Merlin - and it has been there for many years, since they stopped holding the Triwizard Tournament. Even I've never seen it, although I did spend some time looking for its companion device - or the pieces of it, anyway." Harry held up his left hand, clad like the other in a fingerless glove, and tapped the smooth round decoration that was slightly raised from its palm. "Ancient and powerful enough to be effective decoys for the real Philosopher's Stone." Harry paused, thoughtfully, and a drop of sweat trickled down the side of his face. He added, "But I suspect that the Professor only said this because he wanted that information, since he anticipates going free once killed."

"And will he, Mr. Potter?" asked Meldh, gently.

"Some time ago, some researchers with the Tower and the Unspeakables - Mafalda Hopkirk, Dolores Umbridge, Luna Lovegood, Basil Horton, and Nemeniah Salieri - adapted a Dark Detector to be extremely sensitive and able to detect even the weakest of magical energies. It didn't have much initial use, since in any magical area, the background magical energies would swamp it. But more recently, we developed that," Harry answered, pointing at the Lovegood Leaf. "It consumes ambient magic in the air. It's proven to be useful in allowing us to employ Muggle devices alongside magical ones, sir, but when combined with thaumometers, we are able to trace even very faint magical connections such as Floo networks... or a network of Horcruxes. He has many… but he is now separate from all of them except the Resurrection Stone, since they are all outside of the Tower. This is a world apart. But while the Resurrection Stone or any other Horcrux is present in the Tower within the Mirror... yes, he could go free. It is best not to kill him, sir."

"These are things I saw in Mr. Potter's mind, Lord Voldemort, and all quite true," said Meldh, turning back to the box. "You might understand why I was interested, since you have correctly divined that I… implied a rather greater age than is strictly accurate."

There was a long pause.

"Lord Foul," said Voldemort.

"Archon Heraclius Hero," corrected Meldh, still smiling. "But yes, I am known to history as the 'Slithering One' or 'Lord Foul,' thanks to the very effective tales of four famous witches and wizards."

Harry was staring openly at Meldh, awe and disgust and pain all in combat on his face. "You're Herpo the Foul… who invented the Horcrux spell? Who fought Rowena Ravenclaw, Godric Gryffindor, Salazar Slytherin, and Helga Hufflepuff?"

"Yes. Good people, all - or rather, well-intentioned. But even then, in my youth, I saw further than such as they. I knew the dangers of will-work - broaching other worlds and inviting them into our own. Even then, I could not understand why so few wizards understood the lessons of Atlantis." Meldh shook his head, ruefully. "The great school of Hogwarts had been prophesied - indeed, prophecy was perhaps the very thing that led those four to band together, for what else but great glory and great threat could have done so? - and so I attempted to intervene. A mighty stronghold of magical education and research was not in the best interests of the world, and I wished to save us all," said Meldh, agreeably and without a trace of pride.

"You failed and died, if the stories are true," said Voldemort.

"Yes. But I was not gone, thanks to some precautions. And my efforts were noticed by another," replied Meldh. "But of that we shall not speak."

"Very well," said Voldemort. "Then your purpose remains the same? I wonder if Mr. Potter is still able to appreciate the irony? Are you intact in there, behind this spell of control?"

"The Lethe Touch," said Meldh, helpfully, smiling again.

"I have read of it," said Voldemort curtly. "So, Mr. Potter - do you see the irony?"

"Yes, Professor," said Harry, closing his eyes once more and wrapping his arms around his stomach. "It's me. And I can see the irony."

"What is the irony?" asked Meldh, curious.

"We have the same goals - maybe even many of the same values, sir," said Harry. "Or rather, I have one goal now, to serve you as best I can, but before -"

Meldh shook his head and waved his hand dismissively. "I understand, it's all right," he said. "You mean that we both wish to save the world."

"And yet you fundamentally disagree, Mr. Potter. It is not a question of truth or evidence, is it?" asked Voldemort. "You have the same purpose in the same world, and yet you disagree. And how was that disagreement resolved?"

"With force," said Harry, reluctantly. "My mind was altered against my will."

Meldh glanced with interest back and forth between Harry and the box. "I do not understand the messages hidden beneath the surface, here, but I have observed your minions often enough, Mr. Potter, to know that you have no objection to force. You have several individuals in your employ whose efforts are directed almost exclusively to force - stunning Muggles and providing them with new memories as you deem fit."

"Weaponizing cognitive dissonance," said Harry, nodding again, even more reluctantly. "But the Professor is offering me a lesson on dominance, not ethics."

"I see," said Meldh. "Well then, I believe we have spent enough time at this. Enough time here." He adjusted the front of his simple robes, and looked around them. "This is a threat that you did not have the heart to end - a threat that you still call 'Professor.' A threat that has managed to worm within your heart and mind, despite being imprisoned and powerless. The world has nothing to gain from this creature's existence, and much to lose." Meldh did not appear saddened by his words, but neither did he seem happy - or even cold. Rather, he spoke with a quiet and inoffensive resignation. "Unless you have something else you wish to say, Lord Voldemort?"

"Will you entertain argument?" asked Voldemort, calm in his own right.

"I will listen to anything you wish to say, but no, I will not change my mind," said Meldh. "I am sorry. You are too dangerous, and your restraints are too uncertain. My purpose has not changed since the fields of Alto Alentejo, among the broken marble of Estremoz, where I led my tarasque and Dementors in a great battle against four titans from prophecy. Neither the double death of a Hero and his name, that day, nor the long passage of millennia since have altered my purpose, which I have sought in a thousand different ways on a thousand different days. I will not give you a cruel and false hope. Your fate awaits, and will not change."

"I see," said Voldemort.

Harry's hair was wild, half-covering his face. Some strands stuck to one cheek, wet with tears.

"Then let me say this," said Voldemort, speaking with leaden seriousness. "It is not too late."

Meldh smiled, but didn't reply. He listened.

"Truly," Voldemort went on, "you even now have the chance for an equitable and peaceful solution. If you undo your control of Mr. Potter and his little friends, he will not seek vengeance for what you have done. Astoundingly and against all sense, he will be willing work with you - to find a path forward. He believes he is a hero, and he believes heroes must always show mercy and seek the path of nonviolence where possible. He is not troubled by the conflict between effectiveness and mercy that is obvious to you and me.

"To all appearances, you have found an easy victory here. That should be the most obvious of warning signs. Mr. Potter's footsteps are littered with the corpses of those who once thought him their catspaw. And I assure you, as a ragged and trapped spirit who once opposed him, that Mr. Potter's cataclysms are all the more terrible for their lack of malice. His cruelty is beyond even my own imaginings, for it results from misguided mercy… and should you be so fortunate as to survive, you will not even have the consolation of hate.

"Take my advice, old one. Relent. Recant. Retreat."

Meldh waited to be sure Voldemort was done, then mildly replied, "I think not." He sounded amused at the thought. "Your kindness is appreciated, however. Why not simply enjoy the thought that the boy will destroy me in due course? He himself has no knowledge of any such plans, I assure you, but why do you show such benevolence?"

Voldemort laughed. It was a cold, mocking laugh, twisting the limits of the generic male voice. For just a moment, it sounded exactly like the Professor Quirrell that once was: cynical and clever, cruel and caustic. A broken man who was without joy or love, and who found solace only the cold pleasure of ambition fulfilled and dominance achieved. Mentor and monster.

"I am offering you fair warning and a peaceful alternative," Voldemort said, and there was triumph in his words. "If you truly do not understand that these words are the greatest damage I can do to you, then you will deserve your fate."

"I hope that you find comfort in such thoughts," said Meldh, softly. He turned to Harry. "Do what we discussed, please, Mr. Potter. The world is more important than sentiment."

"Yes, sir," Harry said. He pulled his wand out of his sleeve. He and Meldh both walked over to the entrance to the extended space - the narrow corridor buzzing with traps and wards.

Harry pulled a lump of tungsten from his pocket. "Geminio," he cast on it, twirling his wand over its surface. One lump became two, and after a moment, that became four, then there were seven, then twelve, then twenty. Within seconds, metal began to clatter from Harry's palm. He tossed what was left in his hand across the room, scattering it, and the tungsten continued replicating itself even as it flew through the air: thirty-three, fifty-four, eighty-eight, lumps of metal raining down, cracking loudly on the stone and a black box that shivered with red light.

Harry and Meldh stepped back into the corridor, and Meldh gestured at the door. Thin blue crystal grew from the ceiling and floor, covering the entrance. It was translucent, and through its cerulean screen the two wizards watched as the room rapidly filled with replicating metal. Normally, it would decay and vanish before too long. But the Philosopher's Stone, embedded in Harry's right glove, could make it permanent. It was not a trick he'd often used, since it threatened the illusion of "special Transfiguration webs" that they used to explain the feats of the Tower healers.

After a very short time, there was no more room left in the small chamber beyond the blue crystal. The replicating metal filled all available space. The two wizards could no longer see anything but a blue-tinted irregular wall of metal. Harry ended the Gemino Curse with a touch of his will, lowering a trembling wand to his side. His teeth were gritted, and the back of his robes was dark with sweat.

Meldh folded his arms, and they stood there, quietly. Gently, the older wizard asked, "Would it help you to take a moment?"

"Yes, sir," said Harry, laboriously. "I'm sorry… it's difficult to manage my feelings." He shuddered and wrapped his arms around his stomach, clutching himself and bending over slightly.

"I understand," Meldh said. He reached forward and touched the blue crystal screen with one finger, and an opening appeared - no more than a palm-span wide. A few chunks of tungsten fell through and free, but the pressure from above kept most of them in place.

Harry tried to stand up straight and raise his wand, but shuddered again, bending back over. He gasped, "I just… I'm…"

"Let me help you," Meldh said. Gently, he lifted Harry's arm, raising it until the wand in the young man's grip was at the level of the hole in the screen. "You may say goodbye, if you wish."

"Goodbye, Professor!" Harry screamed.

His face reddened as he screamed it again - screamed it as loudly as he could.

"Goodbye, Professor! Goodbye! I'm sorry!"

Screamed the words... to try to be heard through the mass of metal, to try to be heard through everything.

There was a reply. It should have been impossible, really. Harry had cast the Thoughtsay Ritual himself, following the dictates of parchment scrupulously, and it should not have been able to get so loud. But it happened, nonetheless, by whatever trick or manipulation. And that reply was not forgiveness or kindness or pleading.

It was scorn.

"Bah!" howled Lord Voldemort with a cold laugh, a last word of mockery and hatred, and then the voice failed with a warble and squeal of magical sound.

There was silence.

Meldh frowned. "No grace, even now. A sad end. Do it," he commanded.

Harry closed his eyes and touched his wand to the pieces of tungsten in the room. After a moment, they gently slipped out of shape, flowing together, forming a solid mass - an immense plug of metal, filling almost the whole room and burying Voldemort in a metal coffin ten feet thick.

Then Harry lifted his other hand and pressed his gloved palm to the surface of the metal.

And that was the story of Tom Riddle.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Hermione's Mobile Mary, Powis Castle, Wales

May 19th, 1999

The next morning

Hermione awoke with tears on her face. She'd been dreaming of Granville. She could hear the echo of his cry still - hear the joy of it.

"Hermione?" said Esther, pushing open the door to the Mobile Mary gently, peering inside the darkened space. Morning sunlight was visible outside, bright on the gardens of Powis. "Sorry, but there's a message for you from Harry. You asked to be woken? Are you all right?"

Wiping her face on her sleeve, Hermione nodded, sniffling. She sat up. "Yes… just a bad dream. What does Harry want?"

Esther held up a parchment. "Nothing serious, it seems like… he just wants you to come around. Says he has someone he wants you to meet."

Chapter 51: Batter My Heart

O royal Hera, of majestic mien, aerial-formed, divine, Zeus' blessed queen, throned in the bosom of cerulean air, the race of mortals is thy constant care. The cooling gales they power alone inspires, which nourish life, which every life desires. Mother of showers and winds, from thee alone, producing all things, mortal life is known: all natures share thy temperament divine, and universal sway alone is thine, with sounding blasts of wind, the swelling sea and rolling rivers roar when shook by thee. Come, blessed Goddess, famed almighty queen, with aspect kind, rejoicing and serene.

Orphic Hymn to Hera (trans. Thomas Taylor)

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

May 19th, 1999

The same day

Hermione had only a few seconds to think before someone stepped into the cubicle, past Harry.

It was an older man with a pleasant smile. He glanced at Harry, but said nothing. He reached out to put his hand on Hermione's ankle.

"Egeustimentis."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Hermione existed as a fragment of consciousness, while a strange man walked through her mind.

"And you are Miss Granger," mused the man. He stroked the broad fur of one thought, as it wriggled down among its fellows. "Or shall I call you Hermione? Maybe when I know you better." The thought squirmed away from the man's touch.

"I am Meldh," said the man. "It has become necessary for you to be altered to a certain degree. All of your friends have been changed thus, including Harry Potter." He waded through the thoughts that seethed around him in their furry multitudes, plucking at them here and there. "Another Muggleborn… and so much like Mr. Potter, himself. He would be pleased to hear that, I think. There is no romance, there… more worship than anything else, as though you were a statue on a pedestal. But it would please him to hear it."

The mote that was Hermione observed this, distantly.

Meldh touched a tightly-spun wire of dense yellow fog, and it undulated at the contact. "So much that is interesting, here." He flickering his fingers over a series of fog wires, and seized one between two fingers to examine it. "You think a great deal of your 'Returned,' hmm? We will take them into our organization as well, then. Great events are in motion, Miss Granger. Entire armies are moving and preparing, getting ready to crash against each other like great waves. Nations will fall. Worlds will end. We will add your Returned to the ranks of the belligerents… take them off of the map, too."

The wizard smiled, amiably. "But first we must make some changes. One rather important change, laid down upon your brain." He picked at a wire, pulled it free, and moved it. "We begin, Hermione."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Meldh released Hermione, and smiled amiably. "There. All better."

She looked back at her master.

The world shuddered, as though in pain.

A ripple passed through the small white cubicle in the Tower clinic, through Hermione where she lay, bound, on the bed, and through Harry and Meldh. It was as though someone had taken hold of reality by the corners, like a bedsheet, and given it a firm snapping shake.

Meldh said nothing, but shot Harry a questioning look, his lips firm. He stripped back the sleeves of his robes with two rapid movements. His skin had begun emitting golden light, pleasant in color, but pricklish on the skin, and some manner of green-skinned creature, translucent and smelling of sulfur, had slithered out from beneath Meldh's clothing to wrap around his waist. The beast had innumerable jointless legs, like clawed tentacles, and the wide-nosed snout and beady eyes of a great lizard.

Harry looked around, bewildered, sweat on his brow. His hands were trembling.

"What -" began Hermione, her voice a croak.

"My God," interrupted Harry, whipping his head around at her. "You used it, didn't you, Hermione?" His voice was rising into an accusing, outraged shout. "I can't believe you would be so reckless! Don't you realize you've put us all in danger?! You've put the whole Tower - all of England in danger! Are you insane?!"

"What is it, boy?" cut in Meldh, his voice an uncharacteristic snarl. His eyes were narrow and dark.

Harry stabbed an accusing finger at Hermione. "It's the ultimate power in the universe. And you have used it."

Meldh whirled to stare at Hermione, raising his hands in front of him. His palms seethed with black ichor, boiling forth as he glared threateningly. The wizard was all alive with anger, bright-edged and sharp, and it was as though he were a different person. "What have you done?!"

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

January 17th, 1996

Three years ago

Harry set the leather satchel carefully on the table. "Here it is," he said. "Fred says that it was just where the centaurs said it would be."

"And we're sure," Hermione said, staring at the bag, "that it's not a fake, made into a trap that will turn us into frogs or something?"

"The Headmistress, Moody, Mafalda Hopkirk, and Edgar Erasmus have all independently verified it," said Harry. In answer to Hermione's raised eyebrow, he added, "...shortly before their memories were voluntarily wiped."

She pursed her lips, and leaned forward across the table, opening the satchel. She reached inside, and pulled out the Goblet of Fire, also known as the Cup of Dawn. It was a crude-looking thing with a thick rim and rough base. There was no fire or glow about it, and to all appearances was nothing more than a poorly-made wooden goblet.

"This is… underwhelming," Hermione said, frowning.

"That's the cup of a carpenter," Harry said, smiling.

"Is it really -" Hermione began, then frowned again. "Oh, shut up."

"I worked out the language for the contract," Harry said, pulling folded parchment out of his pocket. "They used to use this cup for sporting events and major contracts between magical races, so it's pretty well-understood. Hopkirk explained it to me. It can bind anyone to a contract if their names are placed in it. Only valid contracts - binding two or more people, clearly stated terms, only negative consequences, and so on. But it's famously impossible to evade the penalty clauses."

"It doesn't seem that useful to us, then," said Hermione, disappointed. "We don't need a contract to trust each other."

"The idea of 'negative consequences' is relative," Harry said. He shoved the parchment over to her. "We swear this, and then seal the memories of all of this away."

The proposed contract was lengthy.

We, the oathbound, hereby make contract that at no point shall we be controlled, possessed, or otherwise ensorceled by the same individual, group of individuals, club, coterie, organization ... Should we fail to abide by this bargain, whether it be by fault of our own or the deeds of others … shall suffer the immediate and complete dismissal of all enchantments or alterations of mind present on our persons at that time, including but not limited to… as further specified in Appendix XIV … agreement to this contract shall constitute required loss of memory of all terms and conditions for the contract, as well as loss of memory of the contract itself, as well as the location and status of all agents or objects involved in maintenance of the contract, for the duration of the contract…

It went on.

"You don't think this is paranoid?" she asked, studying the oath, looking for flaws or loopholes. "I mean, even beyond Alastor levels of paranoia. There are other ways to use this… there's an opportunity cost for setting this contingency up. If we hide this thing and erase it from our memories, then we can't use it for anything else. Why not use it to lock in support from signatories to the Treaty? Or even just use it to keep all our aurors loyal?"

Harry picked up the Goblet of Fire, and studied it. "Magic is too big. It's too unpredictable. That's a good thing in a lot of ways, since it means we can't even begin to guess at the possible limits for humanity in a universe full of magic. Exploring and colonizing outside of our light cone, reversing entropy… we can't rule anything out. There are thousands of spells, and tens of thousands more that have been forgotten or mostly forgotten. There are too many possible unknowns. This might actually not even be paranoid enough… I tried to figure a way for this to work for us individually, but you can't contract with yourself." He put the Goblet back down. "Yes, we'd pay a price for doing this. But we have to defend against everything, even the impossible things we don't know about yet. Levels and levels."

Hermione regarded the Goblet of Fire, and nodded, slowly. "All right. Although honestly, I'm not sure why all of these sorts of things have such silly names."

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

John Snow Center for Medicine and Tower School of Doubt (The Tower)

May 19th, 1999

Now

"She has used the Star of Death," said Harry to Meldh, his voice upset and his face sweaty. "And now we're all at risk. Our very existence in Time is at risk. Sir, we have to get you someplace safe!"

The Goblet of Fire… our contract, Hermione thought, blinking rapidly. The memory was there - the knowledge of the contract was present, as though it had always been lurking just out of her mind's eye. We broke the contract, and it has imposed its penalty. The failsafe worked. We're free. She glanced down at the bands of goblin silver across her legs, her waist, her chest, and each forearm, fixing her in place to a strip of silver on the underside of the cot. Well, free in a manner of speaking. Are these restraints for unruly werewolves, or something created just for me?

Meldh pivoted in place, holding one palm towards Hermione and swinging the other towards Harry. Ichor bubbled from between his fingers. Where it dripped on the floor, the surface vanished, leaving a series of divots and pocks in the stone. "The 'Star of Death?' There was no hint of such in either of your minds," declared Meldh, his voice taut with tension and anger.

Smart man. When your captured enemy is making implausible claims about secret weapons, he's almost always lying. And even when he isn't, your enemy's demise will often be the best solution. Better for your health and your reputation to wipe them out immediately.

He needs fear. She glanced at the marks left by the black ichor. Fear of obliteration. Fear of the unknown.

"It's coming," said Hermione. "And it's already altered our past - eating it up from the source. I think… I think it begins from the first moment of its own existence. Even our memories of it. Maybe it… I'm not sure. I only know that it won't stop until it has devoured our time. Yours, mine, and Harry's. We'll be gone." She breathed out, heavily, and closed her eyes. "I'm willing to pay that price."

"You defy the Lethe Touch," Meldh observed, coldly. "I mastered you and I changed you, yet now you are glad of my death." He paused. "There is something at work here that I do not understand."

Hermione opened her eyes again, and saw the Asiatic wizard staring at her with narrowed eyes. She remembered lunch with Reg Hig and Per Aavik-Söderlundh-Ellingsen, and the value of a strategic but subtle slip.

"It doesn't matter what you do," she replied, her own voice as firm as bedrock. "I will not stop the Star of Death." She raised her voice, pronouncing as clearly and coldly as a mountain stream, "Die. And be damned."

He turned to face her, fully. Just behind him, she saw Harry watching, carefully but silently. Good. Don't oversell it. The translucent green creature that clung to Meldh's waist hissed, quietly, and kept its attention on Harry.

Meldh said nothing, either. He only met her gaze with dark eyes. She felt a touch on her mind - the gentlest of probing contact with another's thoughts. Barely a whisper of Legilimency: a thin needle of attack so perfectly honed in its intrusive power that it seemed to have physical form.

Hermione didn't react. Her training had not overlooked the obvious. Her mind was a stone her mind was steel her mind was wax her mind was an ox her mind was a child her mind was herself.

And there was nothing for Meldh to find there but contempt. Die, and be damned.

Meldh said nothing, but she felt the touch on her mind change. The whisper-sharp needle of Legilimency vanished and was replaced by something unfamiliar… a draining emptiness that settled down around her thoughts. It plucked at her from many directions at once, presenting a blankness into which her mind could pour. It was like the last moments of consciousness before sleep, where a thought could occur, linger on the edges of awareness, and then gently tumble away into the darkness.

But Hermione had an answer for that, too. She cast thoughts into that darkness, one after the other, flinging them out into the sucking unconsciousness that lay on her thoughts like a blanket. She hurled memories like weapons, a bulwark of recall that could be offered without loss: the feeling of sunshine on her shoulders as she sat in a field at Powis; the rich ribbons of smell that filled the house when Gran made venison pies; the joyful screams of Granville that shattered the grimness of Azkaban; the click of one chess-piece against another as her father taught her how to castle.

The draining emptiness vanished with that last thought, and she saw a flicker of reaction on Meldh's face. Surprise and suspicion.

Hermione never moved her eyes from his.

"Kурва," Meldh spat at her, his face reddening. "Very well. Another Touch. And I will tear your mind to shreds this time."

You have to get near me to do that, little man, thought Hermione.

He took a step towards her, reaching out for Hermione's restrained arm. The golden light that had been gently emanating from him faded, and the ichor vanished from his palms.

Behind Meldh, Harry drew his wand.

She bucked in place, kicking both legs as hard as she can, straining her stomach, wrenching her arms in place. The goblin silver didn't yield even a little. But she remembered fighting Tineagar in a Tidewater basement - remembered the value of sacrifice. Pain is nothing. Save one life.

Her right arm braced against the restraint, and she twisted it to the side. It broke with the sharp sound of fracturing bone. Pain roared like a lion, savaging her.

Meldh, reaching out for her, lurched backwards in surprise.

Harry raised his wand to point at Meldh. Almost immediately, the green creature wrapped around Meldh's waist hissed loudly, and lunged at Harry. He backpedaled, swatting at the creature as it landed on his chest, shrilly hissing and baring its smoking fangs. Meldh jerked around in shock.

Hermione jerked her arm free, torn hand and forearm still locked in place on the bed, blood pouring out of her like a bolt of crimson fabric. A scream burst from her.

But the end of her backup wand, the Ultimate Ulna, was exposed amid the splintered ends of her bones.

"Lagann. Stuporfy."

The Breaking Drill Hex cleared the way, and the Swerving Stunner didn't even need to swerve: it hit Meldh full in the chest.

The member of the Three didn't fall. He staggered, red flickering energy jolting through him. The green creature on Harry's chest - connected somehow? a sort of magical circuit-breaker? - whipped its head back and exploded in a shower of phosphorescent green sparks torn through with flickering red. In the same moment, the Ultimate Ulna also flared green and red, and burnt itself into ashes. She could smell her own flesh as it burnt.

I'm unarmed, she thought crazily.

Meldh lurched forward towards Hermione, grunting something unintelligible, his face a grimace of rage. He reached for her.

Desperate, she lashed out with her broken arm. The splintered bones lashed Meldh across the face, leaving deep scratches along his cheek. The pain was Fiendfyre on her nerves.

"Hermione!" called Harry, reaching for his dropped wand, eyes wide.

"Hermione," snarled Meldh, arm outstretched, swaying in place.

"Hermione," agreed Hermione, and struck once more with her broken arm, and her splintered bones tore like talons through Meldh's throat. Blood geysered across her chest and face.

The dying man's hand came down on her shoulder, his dark eyes bright with anger. Blood poured onto her from the lacerated meat of Meldh's throat. He tried to speak, to cast a spell, but could produce nothing more than a bubbling gurgle and a mouthful of blood. Meldh grimaced, and his teeth were red.

"Stupefy. Stupefy. Stupefy!" cast Harry from behind him. And this time, mortally injured and bereft of his defences, the spells took Meldh. The member of the Three shivered through with red energy, his muscles locking, and toppled to the ground like a fallen tree.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Oh, All-Nature, Queen, Mother of all things, untiring Mother, exalted, creating, She who tames all, Unmentionable, shining, the Firstborn who quenches everything, who brings the Light! Born of yourself, present everywhere and all-knowing You Blessed One, who makes things grow and rot, Father and Mother of all things, Universal Worker, you who walk forth in an endless maelstrom, conserving, you who uphold yourself through repeated metamorphosis: I pray to you, give me peace!

Orphic Hymn to Demeter (trans. Thomas Taylor)

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

Hermione, shaking, clutched at her injured arm with the other. It had stopped bleeding already, which was a relief. She'd been worried that her innate healing ability had been "dismissed" by the Goblet of Fire.

Across the cubicle, Harry was leaning on a chair, wand in hand. He was shaking, and there was a scorch mark on his cheek. Hermione supposed that had happened when that green creature had exploded - taking her wand with it.

She found her voice, finally, glancing from Harry to the frozen Meldh, and then back again. "The Death Star?"

Harry shrugged, but couldn't stop a smile from spreading on his face. It was an odd contrast with his trembling hands and the sweat plastering his hair to his forehead. "I couldn't… I couldn't think of anything else that sounded plausible and scary enough." He shook his head. "I don't know how we…"

His voice trailed off, and he paled. "Oh, God… everyone else. The Tower, the entire Tower, is magically bound to serve Meldh. He got almost everyone, Hermione. Draco, Moody, Cedric, the aurors, the healers… dozens and dozens of people are still under the effects of that... that… that spell."

"Get me out of this, first," Hermione said, slumping back against the bed. The pain in her arm was fading, finally.

"Buttons thirteen Sangomas," Harry said, and the restraints opened with a gentle click. "I'm so sorry about that, I didn't -"

"No time," interrupted Hermione, "and anyway, don't be stupid. How do we free everyone?"

Harry rubbed his temples, gritting his teeth. "I don't know. There's a counter-spell, but I stopped him from telling me about it. For exactly this reason, as a matter of fact. You cast the spell - which is Egeustimentis - and then you say something else. But I don't know what."

Hermione knelt down next to Meldh, and clamped a hand over his neck. "Get out your medical kit. Maybe we can wake him up and get the spell out of him, somehow."

Harry knelt beside her, opening his mokeskin pouch. "Medical kit," he told it. He opened the small white case as soon as it leapt to hand, taking out Haverford's Marvelous Coagulant and some bandages. "It's been weeks, and I only just found out yesterday that we had finally managed to safely get some things out of Bellatrix Black. You think we can crack this guy in the next few minutes, before someone checks on us? Without him playing puppeteer again?"

"Point taken," Hermione allowed. "But I don't even have a wand, much less my other stuff, so I don't know what we're going to do, otherwise. Can you manage to stun everyone here by yourself? Have you been secretly practicing duelling with Cedric or something?" she asked. She lifted her hand from the injured wizard's throat.

Harry didn't answer, just rolled his eyes as he squeezed orange gel onto Meldh's neck. The blood pouring out of the wizard's ragged throat began to slow, and soon stopped. "Your usual wand is in the meeting room, with the rest of your things. But I have a back-up wand for you. It's actually here in the clinic. I wanted to keep it especially safe, sealed off even from the rest of the Tower in case of trouble." He held out his wand to her. "Take mine for the moment."

Hermione took it from him with her uninjured arm. The wound on the other had closed, but she thought it would be ten or twenty minutes before the arm was usable again. She examined the raw-looking pink skin of the stump, which throbbed with pain in time to her heartbeat. She made a face.

"For now, I'll transfigure Meldh," Harry said. "We can't kill him, since we really might need him to release everyone. Let me have that back for a moment." She handed him back the wand, reluctant despite the obvious necessity. Harry was not a duelist.

He took the wand and held the tip against the chest of the villain's stiff body. Meldh began to shrink and warp in color and shape. Harry glanced over at her. "He was really Herpo the Foul, you know. Inventor of the Horcrux spell."

Hermione nodded, thoughtfully. "That makes sense." She stood up and went to the curtained entrance to their little white cubicle. "That spell… it was enslavement. How long were you like that? How long has he been here?"

"A couple of days," Harry said, quietly. His voice was very small. "It hurt. It was like being at war with myself. Everything in me pushed as hard as it could, but it was like part of my mind had forgotten itself. Couldn't help itself. And it was the most powerful part." He stopped speaking for a moment, staring down at the diminishing Meldh with distant, unseeing eyes. "I worry a lot about addiction. I think that this was what addiction would feel like." Meldh was gone. In his place was a small white rock.

"Then you'll have put at least some plans in place in case something like this happened," said Hermione, firmly. Stay with me, Harry. "How long do we have before someone comes to ch-"

Cedric Diggory pulled back the curtain to the cubicle, flanked by a pair of aurors. He looked startled, opening his mouth to say something. The aurors behind him were quicker on the uptake, and their wands were already drawn. They raised them.

Harry still has his wand. I've got nothing - less than nothing, only one arm. Need to close the distance.

"Είναι ο ίδιος!" called out Hermione, firmly, walking towards them with a bold and unafraid step. Her Greek was abysmal, a basic vocabulary put together in haste before the raid on the Cappadocian fortress of Göreme, but that wasn't important. They have one overriding priority, the same one that was given me: protect and obey Meldh. That's an advantage for me. And they might be the slower for their internal conflict.

They were too well-trained and experienced, however, for any of that to slow them more than a moment. She was still out of reach when they recovered from their surprise, deciding that the better part of service was to incapacitate first and ask questions later. Good for them, that was the right decision. Even if it's massively inconvenient at the moment. The faces of the aurors hardened, and she saw their arms tense again. Cedric's eyes widened in alarm, and he snatched for his own wand.

Hermione thrust out her mind with the smell of blue November and the smell of burning leaves, and threw herself forward in an inhumanly powerful tumble. Her ward of prisms burst into existence, unfolding themselves with a crackle of crystal into a solid wall across the front of the cubicle.

They didn't fall for the gambit. The auror to Cedric's left fired Bertram's Bolts high and low, while the other tracked her with his wand, casting the Stunning Hex at her moving form. As Hermione tumbled forward, she heard the prism-barrier shatter and evaporate, and felt the numbing sting of a near miss.

"Stupefy! Stupefy! Expelliarmus!" she heard Harry cast, just before her tumble rolled her into the trio of aurors. She smashed into and through Cedric's legs with her back, carrying them out from under him. He fell on top of her, thrashing at her as he struggled to bring his wand to bear on her.

One of the aurors gestured a Roger's Shield into being in front of himself, almost effortlessly catching Harry's attacks with the multicolored circle. The other had his wand pointed at her, his mouth open to curse her. Cedric was in the way, but that didn't matter if he was just going to stun her, anyway. The auror was just too far to reach, and she didn't have any weapons. Could she grapple with Cedric and get his wand?

Oh. Cedric.

She seized one of Cedric's legs with her good arm. She had a moment to see him staring at her, horror on his face. Then she heaved on the leg, hauling it as hard as she could upwards and away from her. She couldn't actually lift him off the ground that way - his leg would have come off if she tried, she thought - but he swung along the floor like an enormous club, smashing into the threatening auror's legs. The two wizards fell into a tangle of injured limbs.

The other auror turned his attentions to her, but it was too late. She was on her feet like lightning, and dropped him with a light backhand across the side of his skull. He collapsed, unconscious.

Harry darted forward and stunned the other two. They froze into immobility, still folded around each other and struggling. He threw her the wand, and she snatched it out of the air with her good hand.

"Last cubicle on the end," he said. "Password is 'splendour fifty Buick.' "

Hermione nodded. "Make sure none of these three are too badly hurt."

"Go," Harry said, already reaching for the medical kit.

She leapt over the auror she'd knocked out, into the main corridor of the clinic. The long row of white cubicles confronted her, screened off with sheets. She sprinted the length of the corridor in the blink of an eye, arriving at the other end of the general ward at the same moment as a running auror appeared at the door - Hedley Kwannon. Kwannon's wand was already drawn, Hermione saw.

"Stupefy!" cast Kwannon and Hermione at the same time. As she cast, Hermione lunged to the side into one of the cubicles, clawing out with her mind to raise another wall of prismatic crystal. For her part, Kwannon was unbelievably fast, raising a wall of Azarian Fire and the red mist of Bartolomeo's Reckoning almost at the same time, and still able to bring her wand back to Pflug position. The auror's wards absorbed Hermione's curse, and Kwannon was ready to cast three Bertram's Bolts, each a foot apart from the next. Hermione felt them sizzle past her, the dull yellow hexes missing her only by the grace of her speed and luck.

Hermione sprang to her feet as Kwannon charged through the door. Immediately, Kwannon raised more Azarian Fire, and it was again a cover for an attack. But this time she attacked Hermione's footing. "Orbis." Hermione felt the stone underfoot soften, sloughing away from under her shoes. She's better at chaining and a better shot than me; if I lose my mobility, I'm done, Hermione thought.

For her part, Hermione responded the way Alastor had always taught her: once you know your advantages, press them relentlessly. She sacrificed position and used the stone for her own purposes, charming it into a swirling wall of rock between the two of them. Then she sprang forward, driving her toes hard into the softening floor.

From the other side of the wall, Hermione heard Kwannon chant the first few syllables of the runes of balance: a delaying action. Unfortunately for Kwannon, Hermione simply had no time for more of this.

She threw herself shoulder-first into the stone at full speed, and it yielded before her. She burst through, into a startled Kwannon - still tracing orange symbols in the air - and stunned the auror with a crackling red curse.

Panting, Hermione turned to the cubicle on the end. "Splendour fifty Buick," she said, holding her shoulder.

The plain stone of the wall shifted in one spot, slightly and silently.

Hermione stepped over to the stone that moved, and gently pushed it to one side. It swiveled open on an invisible hinge, exposing a small ledge within the wall.

Resting on the ledge was a wand of elder wood. She recognized it. It had once belonged to Albus Dumbledore, before it passed to Lord Voldemort. He in turn passed it to Harry Potter, who became - as she understood it - the rightful owner, by dint of conquest.

Until he was defeated by Bellatrix Black, she realized. Right before I put my fist through her.

Hermione Granger picked up her wand.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

O Powerful Nike, by men desir'd, with adverse breasts to dreadful fury fir'd,

Thee I invoke, whose might alone can quell contending rage, and molestation fell:

'Tis thine in battle to confer the crown, the victor's prize, the mark of sweet renown;

For thou rul'st all things, Nike divine! And glorious strife, and joyful shouts are thine.

Come, mighty Goddess, and thy suppliant bless, with sparkling eye, elated with success;

May deeds illustrious thy protection claim, and find, led on by thee immortal Fame.

Orphic Hymn to Nike (trans. Thomas Taylor)

Chapter 56: Penultimate

Hermione had a moment to think as she and the Returned climbed through the air away from Hogwarts, zipping over the school grounds towards Hogsmeade. It was a short distance - a few minutes' flight - but she took the opportunity afforded her to think beyond the immediate tactical situation. Strategy, not only the demands of the moment, needed to dictate her movements. And right now, she didn't have any sort of larger strategy.

How could I? How do you fight an enemy that breaks all the rules of the game? Hermione thought to herself. The Three were attacking - Well, now it must be the Two, really, she thought, thinking about the unremarkable white stone that was sitting inside of a small, mundane iron box in the Headmistress' coat pocket. But Meldh had wrought havoc and almost brought the entire world under his control with one spell… It had taken an ancient artifact and years of planning to create a safeguard against that kind of attack, and even then it might have failed if things had gone a little differently. At that last moment, if Meldh had the wits or resources to draw up another spell from his ages of lore, there was literally no predicting what he might have been able to do to her or Harry - even with his throat missing.

The old books were full of fantastical feats and mighty deeds, and attempting to sort out the historical from the apocryphal was more a work of literary criticism than historical research. "Lord Foul" was said to have commanded dementors and basilisks and terresque, but was that a real spell of command that the Three might deploy, or simply a legend that the writer thought was appropriate for a infamous dark wizard?

Normally Hermione would be able to rule some things out - a secret spell from the past that allowed its caster to stop someone's heart without the possibility of dodging or warding, for example. If such a spell had existed, it would have made the one who invented it into an unstoppable force. History would look different.

But according to Harry, Meldh had implied that the Three had been in hidden control of events for generations, which meant that they might actually be an unstoppable force.

"They're using all the powers of the old world," Harry had said, "everything that's always worked for villains like them in the days gone by. But we're going to use all the powers of our new world to match them, and we're going to beat them."

But unless they had some brilliant ideas very soon, she couldn't see how.

Hermione heard a dull popping sound from far below among the trudging mass of mind-controlled Muggles - no, people - and pulled up on her broom. The Returned matched her, and they rose higher yet. They were already too high to be under real threat from rifle fire, even if they hadn't been warded, but there was no point in risking it. She glanced around her, making sure everyone was with her and uninjured. Hyori and Esther rode on either side of her. Charlevoix and Urg followed them, staggered at different altitudes, while Susie, Tonks, Nikitas, and Jessie were spread out in a third, staggered row. Simon's absence was conspicuous.

Simon. My solid rock. Sweet, solid Simon. Gone now. Hermione wished she could have been there - to save him, to help him, even just to hold his hand.

He'd been the first one she'd saved.

It was still been raining when Hermione began pulling open the cell doors. The walls of Azkaban had been battered, and a great jagged fissure had split one of the three sides to the prison; Granville had carried her through and they had landed within, and for the first time in centuries, the broken halls of Azkaban felt the cleansing cool of the rain.

Most of the cells were empty. Most of the prisoners were gone, transferred to the new Howard Prison or simply released. But there were still people here.

One door was stuck. Hermione forced her fingers around its edge, the stone cracking loudly through the patter of rain, and wrenched the door open. Another empty cell - no, there was someone here.

She stepped into the cell, and let gentle orange flame illuminate it. Granville made a small sound, shifting in position on her shoulder. It was a sound of remorse or admonition.

The person was lying on their side, staring up at the ceiling. Rotting alive, with black leprous streaks of infection spreading from great mottled sores, entwined maladies spread across a withered chest. As warm light touched the person's face, they slowly closed their eyes and turned towards her. What did they see when they looked at her - just a soaked teenager with a phoenix and a scared look on her face? Who did they think she was?

She reached out a reassuring hand to the person as she approached.

"My name is Hermione Granger. I'm here to help you."

And now he was gone. Brave Simon.

Her attention snapped back to the present as they passed the gates to Hogsmeade, and she saw new enemies. Not just the endless flood of weapon-wielding Muggles, but two other groups.

A large wedge of witches and wizards in robes was slowly, almost casually, making their way through the mass. They walked in good order right along the stone-paved path from Hogsmeade, as though they were merely a group of forty students returning from a trip to Honeydukes. The Muggles parted before them as though directed by an invisible force. Something to do with the spell controlling the Muggles, or something about the orders they'd been given, or… maybe these are involved in the control or can give directions?

Hermione felt cold run up her back as she recognized - even from this height - some of the enemy. Councilor Limpel Tineagar. Bellatrix Black, with one eye and one arm (her artificial arm, the Gripmain, presumably still lay in the vaults of the Department of Mysteries). Some of the strangers wore markings on their robes that Hermione recognized as the sigils of Grindelwald's death squads, the Hírnökei; she could see the red sword of the Záh Kardja and the red hand of the Veres Kezek. No Grindelwald himself - a small mercy in this tide of nightmares.

And yet even this was not the end, for behind this infantry of dark wizards was a cavalry of monsters.

She recognized the basilisks. The ten enormous serpents were following a lone witch in a green dress, seeming to mimic her movements. As she walked, they swayed to match the swing of her hips, and their gaze was clearly fixed on her back to the exclusion of all else. The basilisks were at least fifty feet long, perhaps more; the portion of their serpentine bodies that they held upright was as tall as a single-storey Muggle home.

Behind the basilisks was another mass of creatures - terrifying things that could only be terresque. They had broad shells on their backs, rough as chipped stone, and moved on six stubby legs with shiny red scales. They were huge - ten feet high, with round black heads as large as a lion's, and great mouths that smoked with some sort of vapour. As they lumbered along, they resembled nothing so much as a mad cross between a tank and a turtle and a parade float.

As both groups came into view and as soon as she grasped what she was seeing, Hermione immediately reacted. They couldn't handle this - not with so few people. She yanked her broom to one side as sharply as she dared, almost colliding with Hyori before the Returned could match her change of heading. Should they be trying to transfigure protective goggles or something, in case the basilisks' stare reached them at this distance? No, no time, and they needed free wands. The important thing was to get back out of sight and warn everyone else. Luna already had one task, but now Hermione had something else for her, too.

The witches and wizards weren't mounted - strange, but in keeping with their lack of hurry in a time of war - and so there was a chance that Hermione and her people might get away before any conflict could begin. She heard a distant shout from below as they wheeled about, but the enemy wouldn't manage more than one or two attacks before the Returned were clear. My God… in addition to a seemingly endless horde of Muggles, we'll also be fighting the denizens of Howard and Nurmengard?

A bolt of green light streaked past, veering wide. It was joined by another, placed more accurately and blistering through the air between Esther and Charlevoix. A thick gust of steam blew into the group almost at the same time, but it was without force at this distance, and the Returned were putting distance between them and the enemy with every moment.

There was no point in engaging, but a thought did occur to Hermione - obvious, in retrospect. She slackened her pace just slightly, and brought her wand to her throat. "Sonorus," she cast, and then bellowed at the top of her lungs, "Egeustimentis Ba!"

There was an immediate response below, as four or five of the witches and wizards began firing on each other. A fireball erupted among the group, cast by one of its number. Hermione grinned, and leaned further into her broom, urging more speed. They still needed to prepare for the monsters.

An odd hooting sound startled her. It sounded like a giant owl - and it seemed far too close, as though it somehow cut through the rushing wind. Hermione jerked her head to the side and looked for the source, but saw nothing. She could see Urg looking puzzled, and knew she hadn't been the only one who heard it.

Then Susie fell out of the sky, tumbling off her broom, slapping at something that was wrapped around her head. Hermione only caught a glimpse of it as Susie tumbled away - a naked thing of skin and teeth, vibrating violently.

And then Hermione was diving after her, her broom vertical, arm stretched out and golden gauntlet reaching. She could hear Susie screaming - shrieking at the top of her voice, louder than a person should be able to scream, agony tearing out of her.

Shouldn't do this no time stupid stupid, she thought, in a confused jumble that didn't shake her from her course in the slightest.

Hermione strained forward, trying to force herself to go faster, to dive more quickly, to reach farther. Susie tumbled away in a tangle of robes and blood, beating at the thing on her face and chest until it fell away, tossed in the wind. The ground rose towards Hermione and Susie, surging up to meet them as they fell.

She reached and reached and

Got her.

As her hand clamped down on Susie's ankle, Hermione kicked herself savagely back, hauling on the front of her broom so fiercely that she felt the wood strain and crack dangerously in her grip. She pulled up into a swoop, the bottom of the arc dipping within arm's reach of a crowd of threatening Muggles, dragging them both back up into the sky without letting go of a drop of speed. The violent motion wrenched Susie badly, and Hermione felt something in the witch's leg give - the hip or knee - but Hermione had her, thank God thank God, she had her.

They rocketed forward, Hermione leaning forward and holding the broom steady with her left hand. With the other, she pulled Susie up, lifting the witch's lower body over the front of the broom.

But Susie was dead.

Her face and chest were a mess of bloody meat, ground and torn as though by some monstrous industrial machine. Her mouth was agape - a lifeless black wound in the shredded flesh.

Hermione's eyes burned with the wind and her rage, and she clenched her jaw. She leaned forward, though, gripping Susie in place. Stay focused. Susie could still be saved.

The rest of the Returned joined her moments later, swooping down to fall in line with her.

Hermione heard more hooting.

No no no what is that?!

Esther pulled even with Hermione, and leaned over. She grabbed one of Susie's arms, pulling on the witch. Hermione understood what she wanted, and helped, seizing the back of Susie's robes and lifting the witch from one broom onto the other, fighting with the other hand to keep their flight steady.

There was another hooting sound, and something collided with Esther, her broom, and Susie. The two witches were gone, as immediately as if they'd been struck from the sky by lightning.

Hermione wheeled in her seat, and saw… something. Not a physical thing so much as a flow of sensations. It was something like the use of wandless magic: the purposeful movement of particular ideas. But this was somehow visible, and moving, and malevolent. A collection of sensations, divorced from sanity and sense.

Large eyes. Black and oily. Wet.

White skin. Flaky, run through with spidering cracks. Ragged in places, as gnawed.

Long, thin limbs. Sparse flesh. Lumpy joint.

Mouth. Smile.

Smile.

And there were more, leaping up around them. Hooting with mirth. They were so fast; Hermione was on a broom at top speed and they were leaping at her.

Without word or order or request, Hyori and Charlevoix broke away from the Hermione and the rest of the Returned. Hermione twisted to see once more, and they flew around and back, in a circle back to where Esther and Susie had fallen. Their curses flew as quickly as they could cast them, but the creatures were too quick and too inchoate. Even the spells that seemed to hit had no effect. They leapt at Hyori and Charlevoix, hooting, and the pair vanished, plucked out of the air.

Hermione turned back around, gritting her teeth again, and her hands tightened on her broom. She fought to stay calm - fought to stay under control.

Esther and Charlevoix. The French witch had once been nearly catatonic, breaking into screams every time she was separated from Hermione. Esther had been very quiet, too, for a time; injured deep within herself by betrayal and her own anger. But the two had found each other during this past year in some new way - Hermione hadn't pried. They were even leaving Powis - they'd just recently gotten a cottage in Godric's Hollow.

Hyori. An enigma, even to Hermione. Laconic and deadly serious, imprisoned for murder, but with some hidden depth that Hermione had never understood. She'd made a game of things in subtle ways, and her sharp eyes had always hinted at thoughts the witch had never revealed.

Susie. Lascivious and sarcastic, delighting in affecting cockney, alluding to a sexuality she used like armor. Like all of the Returned, she'd left some piece of herself with the dementors, but she was bravest of them all in trying to reclaim it.

Hermione, Tonks, Urg, Nikitas, and Jessie flew on, back to Hogwarts and back to help.

Not that Hermione could imagine what help would suffice. What could anyone do in this situation? What weapons did they have that would work?

And again: what did these damned monsters even want?

This didn't make any sense! Why was the enemy entering through Hogsmeade, and not right outside the castle - or for that matter, why not right inside the castle? They didn't know the limits of the spell, but Bellatrix had used it to simply appear within Hogwarts, so why not do that again?

For that matter, why go to war like this at all? Harry had said that Meldh had only said that "a great and fearsome god" was calling for "blood"... part of some larger plan to eliminate magic from the world. That last bit accorded with what Tineagar had said back in Tidewater. That seemed like years ago, now… Tineagar had claimed she was fighting to stop the world from breaking.

They were wasting resources, unless they had some hidden aim. Their plan had been for Meldh to take Harry's place, with Harry in some "new shape" as an enslaved advisor. But preparations for this attack must have started, at the latest, well before Hermione went to the Tower. The Muggle news, she'd learned, had begun reporting disappearances in the morning. So why were the Three essentially attacking each other? It couldn't be infighting or rivalry, since Meldh had known about it to mention to Harry. It was part of a plan. But she couldn't see what that plan's goal might be, in light of the Three's goal of ending all magic. Were they trying to start a war between Muggles and wizards? Or just trying to kill off as many wizards as possible? Or was it just a distraction from a trio of monsters who had no particular regard for the lives of others? And how would they react to the loss of Meldh?

Oh.

Hermione's broom wobbled as she suddenly realized something, letting go with one hand to snatch her bubbler out of her robes. She lay her will upon it, picturing Harry; he answered almost immediately.

"Harry!" she shouted, calling at the top of her voice to be heard over the wind, unwilling to slacken the pace of her speeding broom even a fraction, "Meldh was going to take your place!"

His eyes lit up, and she knew he understood: to the other two members of the Three, the world might not look any different from one in which Meldh had succeeded and was in control of the Tower. They might not have heard her use the counterspell, if they weren't near that group of wizards. They might still think everything was going according to plan.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

It was an uncomfortable moment when Draco realized he wasn't in charge. He arrived in the Great Hall with Mad-Eye and Diggory at his side and twenty aurors in tow (and one Gregory Goyle). Longbottom and Bogdanova were there, and told him that Granger had left operating orders and then had gone flying off to do her usual routine (jumping from really high, getting in over her head, discovering she was actually a bit rubbish at magic, and resorting to punching things like a Muggle). Her plans were good ones, but they still needed someone in command. The Lord Malfoy (now the greatest of that name, one of the handful of people in command of the entire world) drew himself up to his full height and readied himself for the burden.

But before he could begin, Mad-Eye had already taken control from a perch on the rooftop over the great doors.

"You there, get back here - get on that roof, no need to be flying around!" he roared, pointing at one of the groups in the air. "Use the castle and hold this ground! Keep them back, but Hogwarts is stone from the ancients - use it! And for Merlin's sake, everyone put up a bloody bubble!"

Chastened, Draco tapped his wand to his head, casting, "Bullesco." He felt the uncomfortable feeling as a bubble swelled from one nostril, inflating until it encompassed his head.

They went to work.

It soon became clear that standard dueling tactics were useless. There were simply too many of the enemy, and those methods had already failed one group of defenders. It was simple math: even if every auror was able to kill a hundred Muggles, there would still be more.

Instead, they focused on attacks that affected a wide area - not those rare spells that could do damage on a large scale, for those were deeply draining. Instead, they used attacks on the terrain, and innovative Transfigurations.

The fliers dispersed from a height something called "sarin" out among the Muggles, far away from the castle. Within minutes, it began crippling and killing huge swaths of the enemy. At the same time, other fliers dropped large metal canisters that Mad-Eye transfigured; the blastbombs detonated into fiery explosions as they landed among the Muggle horde.

Closer by, defenders picked off those Muggles who managed to reach the top of the hill and the castle walls, and used the Butterball Charm to make it almost impossible to make the approach. Some still got close enough to attack with their weapons - they became targets, too. One fired a ranged blastbomb which leapt from its tubelike gun and blew up against the castle wall, as though it were conjured fire. It did but minor damage to the school, but it was dangerous nonetheless. A massed horde of Muggles, despite their limitations, were a fearsome threat.

It's like the ancient wars, the stories from old, Draco thought, with a tingle of excitement and unease. Muggles dies in droves, and from a perch on a balcony above the great doors, Draco lashed out to protect everything he had come to value, fighting a war he had never really believed would come.

In only a few minutes, he was starting to feel sick. But there was nothing for it. He swallowed hard and leaned over the railing, twirling his wand, "Stupefy! Stupefy!" Two more Muggles fell back, stunned, dropping into a frictionless slurry of liquified stone and vanishing from sight.

A movement from above caught his eye, and he glanced up to see Granger coming back, streaking through the air at top speed. Half of her band of fanatics were gone. But it looked like she was unhurt, he saw with relief.

She dropped down from the sky and swooped down to a stop near Mad-Eye on the roof, out of sight from Draco. "Alastor, there's a force of witches wizards on the way here. Bellatrix and that American witch, Tineagar, and at least thirty others, including some of Grindelwald's old bunch."

"But not Grindel himself," gruffed Mad-Eye. "Makes sense, since they tortured him into insanity twenty years ago."

Draco didn't even have time to be shocked by this news, as Granger went on. "There's worse… ten basilisks and almost as many rock-monster things - from the old legends, the terresque. And… and -"

Her voice ended in a strangled cry before she found her words again. "And something else. I don't know what, some sort of creatures. They're so fast and spells didn't work."

"Harry's in the library," replied Mad-Eye. Then he shouted at someone Draco couldn't see, calling roughly, "You lot, get down here!"

The Shichinin flew in from Draco's left, joining the pair on the roof. Draco turned his attention back to the battle as an explosion concussed the air, claiming another dozen lives, and picked off two more Muggles who'd separated from the pack and nearly reached the castle.

Less than a minute later, the monsters arrived. Draco had never seen anything like them. Giant serpents - basilisks, he knew. Creatures with six legs the size of buildings. They tore through Muggles like the people weren't even there, crushing them underfoot as they stormed at Hogwarts across the castle grounds.

Monsters… what did you even do in a situation like this?

There was nothing to do except handle one situation at a time, and wait for instructions. Three more Muggles reached the top of the slope, clambering on the partially-submerged bodies of their compatriots who had sunken into a sink of slippery stone, and Draco took them down. One of them raised a tube-weapon, but Draco thought he took him down in time.

The next instant, everything went black and pain, jumbled up in a riot of impact. Draco found himself staring at the side of the castle, lying on the stones in front of the great doors.

He lay there, ears filled with white noise, and tried to understand what had happened.

Draco rolled over onto his back, and coughed. It hurt abominably, as though something inside him was torn. But he couldn't stop himself, and coughed again, spasmodically.

He stared up at the roof of the castle. Granger and the Shichinin were in flight again, a tight bunch. They flew down to him, pausing in the air a dozen yards away.

No time for this, do whatever you asinine plan might be, Draco thought, scornfully. Weakly, he lifted a hand, and flapped it in a dismissive gesture.

Granger nodded at him, something unrecognizable on her face. She turned and waved at one of the Weasley twins, Merlin knows which one, and pointed down at something on the ground, out of Draco's view. "Fred!" she shouted, barely audible through Draco's ringing ears, "You guys take those and get high! Wait for my signal!"

Draco put a hand to his forehead, and it came back red and wet. He felt dizzy and nauseous. Bile rose in his throat, and he leaned over to vomit. When he was finished, he'd barely straightened before he needed to throw up again. His legs felt weak, and he swayed in place, staggering to the side as he tried to stay upright.

A strong grip seized his forearm, held it tight, held him in place. Dazed, he looked to find an armored child holding his arm. No, not a child. A goblin, clad all over in shining silver.

"Rest easy, wizard," said the goblin, its consonants guttural. "We'll need you yet."

Draco couldn't quite understand what he was seeing. Something was in his eyes; he swiped at his face with the sleeve of his robe, blinking rapidly as something stung his eyes. His Bubblehead Charm was broken, he realized. He needed to get it back.

But for the moment, all he could do was fight to stand as the goblin let him go. It hefted a spear in its hand, and pointed it down the slope, to where the monsters were raging.

Draco held himself upright, and felt a moment's hope.

Then he heard the strangest hooting noise.

≡≡≡Ω≡≡≡

A solitary figure in plain grey robes, unseen and unnoticed, watched the fighting.

They paused to flick their fingers through the air, whereupon a tracery of crimson light formed a sharp arrow, directing the figure's gaze to the castle itself and an unseen target within.

The figure picked their way carefully up the steep slope towards the Hufflepuff greenhouse, which was damaged and open. Where the way was inconvenient, the ground gently shifted itself, as though the earth itself was trying to be accommodating. The lone individual stepped delicately over broken panes of grass, and slipped inside the school.

They made their way to the library.